<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Ponderings of an Andy - Review</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/feeds/review.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://andrewwegner.com/</id><updated>2020-10-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Review of GitLab's "How to Manage a Remote Team" Coursera course</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/gitlab-manage-remote-team.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-10-26T09:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-10-26T09:30:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Andy Wegner</name></author><id>tag:andrewwegner.com,2020-10-26:/gitlab-manage-remote-team.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My review of Gitlab's Coursera course on managing a remote team and workforce&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#introduction" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a huge fan of &lt;a href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/"&gt;GitLab&lt;/a&gt; - both the product and the company. As the largest all remote workforce,
they are in an enviable position of being an expert on how to manage a team of over 1000 global employees without
having an office. My current position puts me in charge of managing a global, remote, workforce as well but on a
smaller scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When GitLab announced they were releasing a course on &lt;a href="https://www.coursera.org/learn/remote-team-management"&gt;How to Manage a Remote Team&lt;/a&gt; on Coursera, I jobbed at the
opportunity to take it. I want to expand my skill set as a manager of remote employees and the chance to learn some
best practices from GitLab in this area was a good place to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="course-overview"&gt;Course Overview&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#course-overview" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course is split up in to a four week set of lessons and covers about 11-12 hours of material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 1 covers Remote Best Practices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 2 covers Managing Remote Teams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 3 covers Remote Adaption Processes for Organizations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 4 covers Culture and Values for Distributed Teams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final task then is building a remote transition plan for an organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, these were well done. The videos are presented by various GitLab employees and cover a variety
of different aspects in each section. There are various readings assigned too. These provide a ton of information,
especially &lt;a href="https://learn.gitlab.com/coursera-remote-work"&gt;The Remote Playbook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is some GitLab centric information provided and back patting, but it is done in a way that helps to
show &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; certain things are needed - like open and transparent documentation. By the end of the course, you will
know that GitLab has an open handbook for everyone to read and you will know why you should as well. This type
of thing is expected and knowing that the instructors will do some back patting is important too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final project - building a remote transition plan - is peer reviewed. You are presented with a series of questions,
which you answer with a short essay for each and using information presented during the course. When you are done, the last
task you have is to peer review three of your cohort's projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="conclusion"&gt;Conclusion&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#conclusion" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course was information dense and useful. The time estimate is off as the videos take only about an hour each week. Either
I am a faster reader than I thought or they have overestimated the time it would take to read the weekly material. In either
case, I estimate that I spent about 6 hours. It was also nice that, although the course is split into weeks, everything is
available immediately upon completing the previous tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recommend this course to anyone who manages a team remotely or who is in the process of transitioning to remote work. COVID
has given the entire world a crash course in remote work, but this course is a good way to handle and manage those newly remote
workers effectively. It is also a good course to take if your company is planning on extending the work remote environment that
2020 has thrust upon you to last beyond this current pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitLab has done a good job with this course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://coursera.org/verify/23C6VDATPJMN"&gt;&lt;img alt="How to Manage a Remote Team Certificate" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/coursera-remote-manage.png"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="review"></category><category term="technical"></category><category term="learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Rise Gardens Review</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-garden-final-review.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-05-29T10:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-10-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Andy Wegner</name></author><id>tag:andrewwegner.com,2020-05-29:/rise-garden-final-review.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The end of the series about Rise Gardens. What is my final opinion?&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#introduction" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I close out this series with a quick run down of everything, I want to
congratulate &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/27/rise-gardens-raises-seed-funding-for-a-indoor-hydroponic-gardening-system/"&gt;Rise Gardens on closing a round of funding&lt;/a&gt; to the tune of $2.6M this
week. Well done, Rise Gardens!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started this series a little over a month ago to document my new &lt;a href="https://risegardens.com/"&gt;Rise Gardens&lt;/a&gt; indoor garden.
I've covered everything from the [initial opening of the garden][unboxgarden], &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-garden-assembly.html"&gt;garden assembly&lt;/a&gt;,
to [planting the first plants][plants]. I've covered the &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-garden-suggestions-physical.html"&gt;hardware of the garden&lt;/a&gt; and
the &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-garden-suggestions-software.html"&gt;software and subscription service&lt;/a&gt;. During this time, I've watched my plants
sprout, grow and been harvested (at least some).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="harvest"&gt;Harvest&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#harvest" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A month isn't a lot of time for larger plants to grow. My tomatoes and peppers aren't even close to
being ready, but several varieties of lettuce have been for a while. I've had the butter lettuce,
romaine, and red oak already. My arugula is two days away from being ready, according to the app. I think it's
more likely that it's about a week away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each variety has been good. I have favorites, based on tastes, but no complaints about the quality
or taste of the lettuce. Surprisingly, the kids liked all of them too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="5 weeks into growth" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/7_final_review/garden_now.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five weeks into growing, and I have a decent crop growing. On the bottom, there is a couple tomato plants,
some pepper plants, a swiss chard (almost to harvest too), and a tiny little kale plant. I finally got one
of those to sprout. That was my last kale pod, so I'm happy at least one sprouted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the middle there are two basil plants and two chamomile plants. I've got a nursery started with some plants
that will go in this area in about a week and a half. At the top is my lettuce. In this picture, I'd just removed
two pods that had been completely harvested so it is a bit emptier than it had been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the bottom, you can see that I ran some twine to help hold up the plants. This was put in place to help the
tomatoes before their stalks thickened. They had been leaning. Now that they are tall and thick though, they
aren't even touching that twine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks good!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="customer-support"&gt;Customer Support&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#customer-support" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't remember mentioning this in previous posts, but Rise Gardens has good customer support. I've reached out to
them a few times for various questions. Each time I get a response within a couple days and have had my questions
answered. They are friendly and know what they are talking about. Keep doing this Rise Gardens! As you grow, keep
that focus on the customer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="correction"&gt;Correction&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#correction" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my post about &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-garden-assembly.html"&gt;assembling the garden&lt;/a&gt; I mentioned that there is a gap that appears when you
place the small tray covers in place. It turns out, I was putting those trays on backward. This was pointed
out to be by another Rise Garden owner. Thank you for your help!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the picture above, you can see I have those trays in place correctly now. You can also see a long white
stain on the second level that is clearly coming from the exit pipe. This is due to the splashing the water
was doing before I turned the covers around and the lime in my water. When I clean the garden, this will get
cleaned off too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="final-summary"&gt;Final Summary&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#final-summary" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rise Gardens has built an amazing product. It's not going to replace your trips to the grocery store. One garden
isn't going to feed your family. But, it will supplement it. It will provide you with some fresh vegetables and herbs.
It will allow you to grow for more of the year (especially in colder climates).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's also proved to be very interesting for the kids. They love checking the garden each morning to see how big
plants have gotten or how "their" plant is doing. They help out when nutrients are put in and like refilling the
water with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few areas that can be improved though. I think the biggest improvement that could be made, physically, is
adding leveling feet. If the next iteration has adjustable feet, that solves the largest problem I had during assembly:
how do I make this thing level?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other areas of improvement are related to the software and subscription service. I mentioned these in my &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-garden-suggestions-software.html"&gt;post
about the software&lt;/a&gt;. Personally, I think the suggested times are a bit aggressive for plant harvesting.
I'm continuing to watch, but based on the lettuces that have been harvested so far, the software tells me they are ready
much earlier than they are. The subscription service could use a few additional features - mainly the ability to schedule
selections out a few months and the newest seeds. I still don't see those and I think I'm going to miss them for June, because
my shipping day is soon. I'll try again for July.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the wishlist of items I have, I'm hoping the round of funding they received can be partially used to meet some of these.
On the software side, I'd love an API to pull back previous readings. On the hardware side, a light sensor and more lighting
options would be amazing. If I had to pick between the two, I'd pick that API though...I am a programmer, so take that
opinion with that bias in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="would-i-get-it-again"&gt;Would I get it again?&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#would-i-get-it-again" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I absolutely would get this again. This is a great in door garden. It grows way more than herbs. It's large enough to grow big
plants. It's expandable to grow &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; plants. It's easy enough to not kill plants. With a few improvements, I'd have no complaints
at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="update-oct-2020"&gt;Update: Oct. 2020&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#update-oct-2020" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first full harvest took place in late August/early September. I was reasonably pleased with most of the plants. I started
the second crop a couple weeks ago, hoping to put some lessons learned into practice to do ever better this round. A few problems
I had with my first crop:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I planted to many tomato and pepper plants. They grow larger than the shelf space and started growing up the sides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I planted kale about two weeks after my first batch of seeds and by the time it was transferred to the garden it was tiny and overwhelmed by larger plants&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cucumbers had a lot of buds, but few fruits. I think this is because I didn't prune well enough.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The pepper plants grew very large, produced many flowers, but didn't product a single pepper. I suspect part of this is due to pollination and competition with the tomatoes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this second crop, I've spread of the plants that grow large much more and will end up having empty space in the garden because they will
quickly overwhelm the other plants. I've put lettuce and herbs on the top shelf and filled it reasonably well. I've put two cucumber plants on the middle
shelf and will work on pruning them better and shaping the direction they grow so that they remain on this level instead of growing everywhere. Finally, I'm
only doing one tomato and one pepper plant this time. I'm hopeful that I get some peppers. The tomatoes were very good, but with only one plant I am hoping
it have more room to grow and less competition.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="review"></category><category term="garden"></category><category term="hydroponics"></category></entry><entry><title>Rise Gardens App/Subscription Improvement suggestions</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-garden-suggestions-software.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-05-24T23:45:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-24T23:45:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Andy Wegner</name></author><id>tag:andrewwegner.com,2020-05-24:/rise-garden-suggestions-software.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Several suggestion for the Rise Gardens app, their subscription service and product as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#introduction" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The [garden has been opened][unboxgarden]. The &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-garden-assembly.html"&gt;garden has been assembled&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/nursery-unboxing.html"&gt;nurseries were
opened&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-garden-planting.html"&gt;first plants have sprouted&lt;/a&gt;. I've had my first lecture harvest (more on
this next time). While waiting for that harvest, I offered suggestion on how to &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-garden-suggestions-physical.html"&gt;improve the hardware&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, after about a month of growing, monitoring and watching the sprout go from seed to plate, I've been
using the application almost daily. I have thoughts on how to make it even better. I have thoughts on how to make
the subscription service better. I'll share those below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="mobile-application"&gt;Mobile Application&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#mobile-application" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the selling points of the &lt;a href="https://risegardens.com/"&gt;Rise Gardens&lt;/a&gt; is the mobile application. It's built to
help you maintain your garden. For the most part, it works well. But there are some warts that need to
be ironed out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am using the Android application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="loading-screen"&gt;Loading Screen&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#loading-screen" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Launching the application presents you with the Rise Gardens splash screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Rise Garden App splash screen" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/6_app_suggestions/riseapp-loading.png"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn to love this splash screen. On a good day, it will show for a few seconds. On a bad day, the application will
hang forever. There is a simple work around, force close the application and relaunch it, but that's rather annoying.
I estimate that I encounter this problem every three to four times I launch the application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="login-screen"&gt;Login Screen&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#login-screen" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I've made it past the loading screen, I find that every four to five days my log in information is forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Rise Garden App login" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/6_app_suggestions/riseapp-login.png"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, every few days I have to log back in. It's also important to point out here that this log in is not
the same as the login you use on their website. My login on the website contains a &lt;code&gt;+&lt;/code&gt;. The application
rejects that form of email address. Since I usually use &lt;code&gt;+servicename&lt;/code&gt; to keep my login information easier
to remember, this is rather annoying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can stay logged into Slack, Hangouts, Gmail, NextCloud, and countless other applications on my phone
indefinitely. I should be able to do that same here too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="plant-information"&gt;Plant Information&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#plant-information" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the nice things about the application, in addition to it's ability to tell me how many and what kind
of nutrients to add, is suggestions on how when to harvest your plants. Unfortunately, I don't think it's
very accurate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This accuracy is something I'm aware of and am keeping in mind as I add nutrients too. If I can't trust one
area, can I really trust the other? So far, with four different types of lettuce harvested, I don't see a
reason not to trust it, but that thought is still in my head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is it inaccurate?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Red Oak Harvest Day Suggestion" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/6_app_suggestions/redoak-harvest-day-app.png"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On harvest day, this is the information presented by the application. There are a few things to
notice in this screen shot. First, "0 days to harvest", yet still showing the "Mid-growth" data.
Second, this didn't change to "harvest" until a full day later. Thinking about it now, I suspect
the datetime of when I added the plant to a nursery was recorded, not just the day and it's going
by "hours since planted", to display the stage information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Red Oak on Harvest Day" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/6_app_suggestions/redoak-harvest-day.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the red oak lettuce on harvest day. This...is not ready. I will fully admit that I am not
an experienced gardener, but this is a tiny little plant. I waited almost two full weeks after this
picture was taken to actually harvest the plant. It had grown much larger by then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the same type of problem with all of my lettuces. They all reached "Harvest day", but
were not ready to be harvested. The other plants I have in the garden at the moment are
longer growing and aren't to the flowering stages yet, so I'll watch for those stages in the
application versus reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="subscription-service"&gt;Subscription Service&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#subscription-service" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things I really like about Rise Gardens so far is the monthly subscription service,
which sends plants that I've selected and nutrients to grow them. My shipping date for May
just missed their newest plants, but I'm looking forward to getting a few of those in June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, I do have a few suggestions for how to make the subscription service amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="multipacks"&gt;Multipacks&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#multipacks" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things that I was sent during the shipping delays was variety packs of seeds.
I covered these in my post where I &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/nursery-unboxing.html"&gt;opened the nurseries&lt;/a&gt;. The subscription
service doesn't allow this type of package. Instead, it ships four pods of an identical
plant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd like to try mint, or cat nip or a couple herbs that I haven't had or use very infrequently,
but I don't need four pods of these plants. Instead, if I could create my own
variety packs I'd be more willing to try some newer plants. This is how I got the
red oak lettuce and the kale that is in the garden now. I wouldn't have gotten four
pods of either of those, since that's just not what I need (or want, in the case of kale). But a
single pod...sure. Might as well, and the kids can try something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="plan-out-multiple-months"&gt;Plan out multiple months&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#plan-out-multiple-months" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plants are shipped out once a month. About ten days before that, I receive an email saying
that my shipment is coming up. Five days before shipping I have the ability to go pick the
plants I want and they are immediately locked in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd love if this flow could go out multiple months. Instead of worrying about making sure
I hit that five day window to make selections, let me pick the plants I want for the next three
months or so and allow me to change those until a few days before shipping. Then I know what I'm going
to be getting and if I decide that I don't like something or want to try something else in a
few months I can still go change it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="subscription-plants-vs-store-plants"&gt;Subscription plants vs Store plants&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#subscription-plants-vs-store-plants" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I missed the availability of new plants for my May shipment. I was looking forward to trying some of
these for June. It turns out, the new plants aren't listed in the list of plants I can
select for my subscription. This is incredibly disappointing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="wishlist"&gt;Wishlist&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#wishlist" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have two items that I really think would make Rise Gardens fantastic and both are software!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="access-to-old-water-readings"&gt;Access to old water readings&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#access-to-old-water-readings" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know the application sending my water readings somewhere. I have to log in, and the
application doesn't work when the internet is down (tried...doesn't load). Give us the ability
to pull those old readings via an API call so that I can plot them. I love data and I love
visualizing date. More information via an API call would be even better. Things like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How long the lights were on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Water level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suggested nutrients to add&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suggested pH balance to add&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe if enough people can see and play with their old data we can even make some suggestions
on what would work better. As it stands though, we don't have access to it. We put in water readings
and that's it. It's gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd really love the ability to pull that old data back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="allow-better-light-control"&gt;Allow better light control&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#allow-better-light-control" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now light control is pretty limited. You pick a time for them to turn on and a number
of hours for them to stay on. That's it. (The hour thing is why I thought about when the
plant status shifted from "Mid-growth" to "Harvest" as well)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Light control" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/6_app_suggestions/light-schedule.png"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd like the ability to be able to turn these lights on and off through out the day. As the sun
crosses the sky, there are hours where the plants are in direct sunlight. I could turn the lights
down to 50% intensity during those hours or off all together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two open ports on the controller. A piece of hardware that can detect light level
could be used to control on/off or light intensity level. Obviously you couldn't put there right next
to a plant, because the LEDs would affect the sensor, but put it on a post and it could tell if you if
the sun was shining on the garden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This type of thing could also be used in different seasons to determine when to turn the lights on
or off automatically. I can use natural light for part of the day, but when the days get shorter, I need the
lights to stay on longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#summary" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm nearly done with this series. I am only planning one last post - a final summary of everything
so far and a quick summary of first harvests (I think it'll only be lettuce at that point).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here I've covered the things that have frustrated me (application loading/login), things that
can be improved (plant information) and offered a few suggestions to make the software and subscription better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I think everything I've mentioned is do able with some development time. I am looking forward to
how Rise Gardens continues to improve the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that is very disappointing though, is that the new plants - cucumbers, bean mascotte, celery, catnip, and
several more - aren't even available as options when selecting my next subscription plants. I hope this is
resolved soon, because I really want to try some of these new plants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next post will be the &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-garden-final-review.html"&gt;last in the series&lt;/a&gt; and will cover harvest and my final, overall impressions of the garden.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="review"></category><category term="garden"></category><category term="hydroponics"></category></entry><entry><title>Rise Gardens physical improvements suggestions</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-garden-suggestions-physical.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-05-05T10:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-05T10:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Andy Wegner</name></author><id>tag:andrewwegner.com,2020-05-05:/rise-garden-suggestions-physical.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Everything is set up and sprouting. While I'm waiting for a harvest, I have some thoughts on how to make the new garden even better.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#introduction" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-gardens-unboxing.html"&gt;opened the garden&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/nursery-unboxing.html"&gt;opened the nurseries&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-garden-assembly.html"&gt;assembled the garden&lt;/a&gt;.
I've &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-garden-planting.html"&gt;planted my first pods&lt;/a&gt; and am now eagerly awaiting a harvest from the new &lt;a href="https://risegardens.com/"&gt;Rise Gardens&lt;/a&gt; garden.
While waiting, I have some time on my hands, so this post is an overview on what I really like and what I think can be improved.
I'm going to just cover the physical garden in this post, and in the next one I'll go over some improvements that would make
the mobile application and subscription service amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="improvements"&gt;Improvements&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#improvements" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's start with what hasn't been great. It's customary to do good news, then bad news, but overall I am
very pleased with the garden so far. Granted, I'm not even at my first harvest yet, but first impressions
have been good. I wanted to end the post on the "good" things about the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="packaging"&gt;Packaging&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#packaging" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Packaging has been a mixed bag. Packaging of seed pods and nutrients, has been flawless. Packaging of the garden, itself,
was less so. As I pointed out in my post where I [opened the garden][unboxgarden], there were areas where packaging just
didn't hold up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Loose screws" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/5_suggestions/scratched_tray.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The screws broke out of their paper bag and scattered all over the inside of the tray. This particular tray has a few scratches on it
that the other two levels do not. I presume it is from the sliding screws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My suggestion here is to either put the screws into a plastic bag instead of the paper one, or put the paper bag of screws into
a little box. A box the size the pods arrive in would be perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Scratched Top" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/5_suggestions/scratched_top.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My top shelf was also scratched. This was stored right next to the bottom shelf - with drawers - and both parts are
metal. I assume they rubbed together during shipping, causing the scratch. I think the easiest way to prevent this would
be to add some small barrier between the two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Antenna Smudge" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/5_suggestions/smudged_anntena.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, for the packaging complaints, we return to the small little antenna. This looks like it was picked from a warehouse
bin by a worker with dirty hands. That's not uncommon for that line of work. My suggestion, in this case, is to have the antennas
stored in some kind of protection - a small plastic bag, perhaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="seeds"&gt;Seeds&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#seeds" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm now about three weeks into my first set of plants, and while a majority of them sprouted, there were several that did not. I know that
not all seeds will sprout, but if I'm getting only four pods of seeds per box and one of those doesn't sprout, that's an
expensive failure rate over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my first transplanting, 7 out of 18 plants didn't sprout after 10 days. After 14 days, those seven still had not sprouted,
but a new set of pods had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I don't have a suggestion on how to improve this right now. As I watch the next round of plants, and my May seeds
when they arrive, I'll be watching failure rate carefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, this is my biggest and only major complaint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="adjustable-feet"&gt;Adjustable Feet&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#adjustable-feet" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have three items that I think would make an immediate improvement on how the system is physically assembled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Lack of adjustable feet" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/5_suggestions/cardboard_level.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something I mentioned in my &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-garden-assembly.html"&gt;assembly post&lt;/a&gt;, was that the area my garden sits in is not perfectly level.
The garden needs to be level though, so that the water flows correctly. My solution to this was cardboard box slices the
length of the foot, so that we could level it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My suggestion though, is to add adjustable feet. This eliminates the need for users to come up with a way to level a
garden that is 50+ pounds that isn't supported by the company. It'd also look much nicer than 6-7 slices of cardboard
stuffed under one leg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="light-sensor"&gt;Light Sensor&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#light-sensor" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next item on my wishlist would be a light sensor. The controller has two unused ports. A light sensor could fit into one
of those ports and could be used to automatically decide if the overhead lights should be on and at what intensity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the year passes, the sun rises and sets at different times of day. I received my garden after day light saving kicked in this
year, but I am curious how it handles that too. Right now, the lights are controlled by the application to come on at a specific time,
stay one for a specific number of hours and then turn off. My garden receives sunlight throughout the day. I'd like to use the overhead
lights to augment that natural light. If it's a cloudy day - turn on the lights. If it's during that time of day where the sun goes
over the corner of the room so the garden is in shade, turn on the lights. If it's early in the morning and the sun is shining on the
plants, but it's just not the intensity recommended, turn on the lights at an appropriate intensity to augment the sun. As it rises and
places the garden in more direct sunlight, lower the lights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="wire-harness-around-controller"&gt;Wire harness around controller&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#wire-harness-around-controller" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The garden has some nice groves built into it to hide the wiring for the lights. It works really well and makes the garden look
nice when you are looking at the plants, or showing off to family members. But, this nice wiring solution doesn't exist once everything
is inside the cabinet. It's a giant free for all of wires. There are light wires, the pump power wire and the power cord for the whole system.
It is fortunate that the wires are long enough that things can be moved and adjusted, but it also means that there is a mass of
wires that hang around in there. A harness of some kind to keep these wires in the correct location would be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-good"&gt;The good&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#the-good" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With my list of complaints and wish list items out of the way, let's go over what has been good about the garden.
Let's make it clear that, apart from my concern about the number of seeds that didn't grow, the scratches and other
packaging things I mentioned are small and easy enough to ignore. The smudged antenna cleaned up and the scratched top can't be seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="craftsmanship"&gt;Craftsmanship&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#craftsmanship" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The design of the garden is fantastic. Assembly instructions are clear. At first they appeared to be
long, but after using them during assembly, that's because they are complete. There were no missing steps. The
components fit together well, the hardware needed to assemble the garden was all provided and nothing was missing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kids helped to assemble it, and I believe that's a testament to how easy it is to put together. They knew what to
do and how to help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system is solid. I am confident it's going to hold the weight of the water and the plants. The biggest thing I need to
worry about is a power outage, which would drain the water (due to gravity) in the basin in the cabinet. If this happens
soon after I refill the water, I suspect it'd overflow. It'll happen at some point, so we'll see how it works out. But,
apart from using a larger basic for a three level garden, I don't think there is anything that needs to change here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="support"&gt;Support&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#support" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've reached out to Rise Gardens support a few times now for various questions I had. I did this both pre-purchase and
post-purchase. In all cases, support has provided me with accurate and helpful answers within a day or two. During the
delivery delays, the company continued to communicate with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If they keep this high quality customer support and open communication thing going, they will do well in building
customer loyalty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="it-works"&gt;It works&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#it-works" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rise Gardens is a young company. It's been my experience that young companies don't always turn out high quality
productions on their first iteration. Rise Gardens has show that experience is not the rule. Everything worked as
expected when I assembled it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pump, the electronics, the assembly instructions. It all just works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#summary" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The physical hardware of the garden has a few areas where improvement would take a great product to even another
level. The packaging could be improved to reduce some of the cosmetic complaints I have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a great design. Rise Gardens has clearly put in the time to design something that works as expected,
but is easy to set up, maintain, and use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my next post, I'm going to cover some more &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-garden-suggestions-software.html"&gt;improvement ideas focused on the mobile application and
subscription service&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="review"></category><category term="garden"></category><category term="hydroponics"></category></entry><entry><title>Planting the first crop in the Rise Garden</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-garden-planting.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-05-01T10:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-01T10:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Andy Wegner</name></author><id>tag:andrewwegner.com,2020-05-01:/rise-garden-planting.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Planting the first crop in the garden&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#introduction" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-gardens-unboxing.html"&gt;opened the garden&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/nursery-unboxing.html"&gt;opened the nurseries&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-garden-assembly.html"&gt;assembled the garden&lt;/a&gt;.
In this post, we plant the first round of seeds, set them in the nursery and wait for them to grow. Let's
continue on this new hydroponic journey with the &lt;a href="https://risegardens.com/"&gt;Rise Gardens&lt;/a&gt; indoor garden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="planting-pods"&gt;Planting Pods&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#planting-pods" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my post about &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/nursery-unboxing.html"&gt;opening the nurseries&lt;/a&gt;, I had pictures of what the seed pods look like. These pods
fit very easily into the pod holders and then slip into the nursery trays. With the variety packs and first
round of seeds we received, it was time to pick what to plant first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first decision we made was that we wouldn't try to grow everything all at once. I can only eat so
much lettuce or so many peppers at a time. I don't want everything ready for harvest all at once. So, we had the kids
fill one nursery while we filled half of another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our initial selections were tomatoes, peppers, two types of lettuce, some chamomile, and basil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A full nursery" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/4_planting/full_nursery.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kids filled their nursery. We recorded which plant was which in the Rise Garden app, filled the water level as
appropriate, and set it in the sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A half full nursery" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/4_planting/half_full_nursery.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We planted half a nursery's worth of plants, filled the water level, and set it in the sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="App with plants in the nursery" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/4_planting/nursery_app.png"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With everything planted, we updated the app, and started waiting. Let's see how these grow!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="three-days-later"&gt;Three days later&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#three-days-later" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Day 3 - Chamomile Sprouts" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/4_planting/day_3_chamomile.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each morning the kids ran down to the nurseries and looked inside eagerly to see if anything had grown. On day three,
we saw our first sprouts - chamomile. The kids were excited because this was in their nursery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="day-6"&gt;Day 6&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#day-6" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Day 6 - Lettuce, Swiss Chard, Tomatoes, Chamomile" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/4_planting/day_6.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On day six, the kid's nursery had several sprouts. In the image above, you can see a couple lettuces, some swiss chard, the
chamomile, and a small tomato sprout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Day 6 - Lettuce" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/4_planting/day_6_2.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The adult nursery was much less green. We have some lettuce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="transplanting"&gt;Transplanting&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#transplanting" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ten days after the initial pods were put in to the nurseries, we had sprouts that were touching the roof of the nursery.
I figured it was time to transplant some of the more mature ones. Even though we were a week and a half later, there were
not sprouts in all of the pods. We didn't transplant those.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Transplanted Lettuce" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/4_planting/transplanting_2.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we can see the lettuces transplanted to the top layer of the garden. Lettuce doesn't grow tall, so it doesn't
need the extra space provided on the bottom layer. It's also a single harvest, and should grow relatively quickly. We
figured the top level would be great for the faster cycling plants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stuck the larger plants - swiss chard, tomatoes and peppers - on the bottom level and left anything else for the middle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In total, eleven out of 18 pods were transplanted. The other 7 didn't have sprouts yet. The hope is they will in a few days.
If not, that's a fairly high failure rate and we'll have to figure out something else to plant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the first round of plants in the garden, each of us picked one additional pod to plant and added that to the nursery for
the next cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#summary" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've finally made it to the garden. Unfortunately, the next step - harvesting - is a ways off. Even the fastest plants are at least a month
or more away. That's fine though, by the time we can start harvesting, we'll be ready for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm a little concerned about the number of pods that didn't sprout. It is our first attempt though, so maybe it was a
combination of which plants were together and which took in more water. We'll be experimenting with different groupings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kids continue to be super interested in this, which is exciting to see. They've grown attached to some of the plants
they've never eaten before, both in the current round of plants and in the plants now in the nursery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next in this series is my &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-garden-suggestions-physical.html"&gt;impressions so far&lt;/a&gt;, along with a set of changes that would be nice to make the product even better.
This will cover both the physical hardware and the electronics/automation side too.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="review"></category><category term="garden"></category><category term="hydroponics"></category></entry><entry><title>Assembling the Rise Garden</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-garden-assembly.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-04-26T01:10:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-26T01:10:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Andy Wegner</name></author><id>tag:andrewwegner.com,2020-04-26:/rise-garden-assembly.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Assemble the new Rise Garden&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#introduction" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's time to assemble the &lt;a href="https://risegardens.com/"&gt;Rise Gardens&lt;/a&gt; indoor garden. In previous posts you can find the
process of &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-gardens-unboxing.html"&gt;unboxing the garden&lt;/a&gt; and the process of &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/nursery-unboxing.html"&gt;unboxing the nurseries&lt;/a&gt;.
Today, we assemble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rise Gardens makes the following claim on their web page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within an hour, you can assemble your garden, connect your app, and plant your first herbs and veggies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoiler: If you don't have children helping, you can definitely hit that one hour mark. For me, the kids wanted to help
assemble, so it took about an hour and a half. Not a big deal. It was a good family project and assembly was fairly easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="assembly"&gt;Assembly&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#assembly" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The assembly manual that we pulled out while &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-gardens-unboxing.html"&gt;unboxing the garden&lt;/a&gt; is misleading in how complex
the process it. It is a fairly thick manual, but it turns out that is because Rise Gardens has documented the
process very well. Most pieces just fit together, get a couple screws and you keep working your way up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="lower-shelf-and-level"&gt;Lower Shelf and Level&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#lower-shelf-and-level" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process starts at the base. It's important to note, and it is noted somewhere in the manual, that the
garden needs to be level so that the water flows correctly. If it's not level, water has this weird thing
about not going where you expect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stuck this in a sun room built on a concrete slab. It's not the most level thing in the area. But, with a
level and some ingenuity we solved that problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Lower Shelf and Lowest Level" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/3_assembly/lower_brackets.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The metal shelf sits an inch or two off the ground once the feet have been attached. The screw holes on the bracket
are designed to catch holes built into the shelf. Then they are tightened into place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Lower Tray" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/3_assembly/lower_tray.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lower tray operates on the same principal. The tray catches on, then is screwed into place with the
included allen wrench.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="upper-levels"&gt;Upper Levels&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#upper-levels" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Middle Brackets" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/3_assembly/middle_tray_brackets.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next two levels are installed by adding the extensions for the level. They attach via a screw to
each upright post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Middle Tray" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/3_assembly/middle_tray.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These trays are also attached the same way. On the bottom of these trays is the light that will shine down
on the level below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Assembled without trays" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/3_assembly/assembled_no_trays.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding the third level is the same as the second. It is topped with the light. If you look closely at the
right foot in this picture, you'll notice we have wedged several layers of cardboard under the foot to
ensure the garden is level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="plumbing"&gt;Plumbing&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#plumbing" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plumbing was as easy to add as the trays. On the lowest level, we added the thick flexible tubes into the basin
below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Flexible tubes into water basin" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/3_assembly/water_basin_plumbing.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The short tube in the back is the pipe that will go up to the plant trays. The longer front one is the water return.
I didn't capture a picture, but the small flexible tubing we unboxed earlier actually will go inside the back tube.
This is different than I envisioned while unboxing it, but frankly makes a lot of sense. This is a thick pipe and I
didn't understand how we wouldn't just flood the system with that much water. The small tubing is much better suited
for the task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Plumbing and plant trays" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/3_assembly/plant_trays.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The inflexible black pipes fit into the trays. In the picture above, you can see the plumbing pipes on the left
hand side of the garden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The water will flow from the basin at the bottom, all the way to the back top. It will flow around the edge on the right
and drain down to the lower level. This will repeat for the second level and then the first and flow back into the
water basin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="testing-the-system"&gt;Testing the system&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#testing-the-system" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With assembly done, it was time to test the lights and add the water to look for leaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Lights" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/3_assembly/lights.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Light check went well. They work at full power and 50% power, as expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding water to the basin and trays and turning on the pump went better than expected too. Water and I
don't always get along. In this case though, water went up and cycled through as expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, there was one aspect I didn't like about plant trays and the water. Each level has three
large plant trays with four holes each to support twelve plans on the level. There is also a gap
by the plumbing that has a small black covering too. That covering doesn't fit though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Gap between pipe and tray" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/3_assembly/gap.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a gap that forms, because the output pipe on each level prevents this covering
from sitting flat. When the pump was first turned on and for the first few hours, we noticed
that water was splashing out of this gap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Outpipe doesn't fit under tray" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/3_assembly/gap_pipe.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see here, the output pipe and it's 90 degree elbow doesn't fit under the black
tray covering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is something I'll have to keep an eye one. I have had the system running for about
a week, but the time this was posted. The first day or two, while the water level was high,
I noticed this splashing. As the water level got lower though, I noticed less and less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#summary" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assembly was incredibly easy. The kids helped do almost all of it. Plumbing was also easy. Almost,
plug and play, easy. I give huge props to Rise Gardens to making the assembly so simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have one big complaint, but it's not related to assembly. It's related to the tray
gap I mentioned above. I really wish the output pipe didn't get in the way of the
black tray coverings, so that it could sit flat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have one suggestion. In the next iteration, put adjustable feet on the bottom of the
upright brackets. I can't imagine I'm the only one with an uneven floor, and it'd be so
much easier to level it with some adjustable feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The build quality is good, minus that tray fitting. It feels very stable. I've had the water running for a week now
and the plants in the nursery are getting close to the point where they can be transplanted to the
garden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up, &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-garden-planting.html"&gt;planting the nursery and watching the seeds sprout&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="review"></category><category term="garden"></category><category term="hydroponics"></category></entry><entry><title>Unboxing garden nurseries</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/nursery-unboxing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-04-24T10:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-24T10:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Andy Wegner</name></author><id>tag:andrewwegner.com,2020-04-24:/nursery-unboxing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;With the garden unboxed, it's time to look at the nurseries. Our seed have to start growing somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#introduction" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-gardens-unboxing.html"&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt;, I opened all of the boxes related to my new indoor, hydroponic
garden from &lt;a href="https://risegardens.com/"&gt;Rise Gardens&lt;/a&gt;. Today's post goes over the opening of the
three nurseries I received. Let's continue my review of the new Rise Gardens farm!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned in my &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-gardens-unboxing.html"&gt;first post&lt;/a&gt;, that there were shipping delays with the garden. One
of the things that Rise Gardens did to make up for this was ship additional nurseries,
nutrients and seeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nurseries showed up a week before the garden did. Had I been planning properly, I would have
set them up at that time. That way when the garden arrived I'd be a week into waiting for my
sprouts. Alas, I did not, so the garden was assembled the same day the nurseries were started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh well. On to the unboxing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-unboxing"&gt;The Unboxing&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#the-unboxing" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Boxes of nurseries" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/2_unboxing/nurseries_boxed.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nurseries showed up in three boxes, all taped together. This should have been my first indication
that the company loves tape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Inside of the boxes" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/2_unboxing/box_1_seeds_instructions.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boxes two and three had identical contents. Box one had a couple extras. The first extra
was this nice quick start guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Quick Start - Inside" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/2_unboxing/inside_instructions.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It very quickly covers what's in the three boxes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nutrient Sensor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Batteries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nutrients&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plant Holders (12 for the nursery, plus 6 extra for the next round of plants)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seed packs. It says 4, but boxes two and three actually had five seed packs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also gives you a quick overview of how to use the nursery. It's pretty simple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take the cover off a seed pod&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't dump out the seed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Place it in the nursery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put in the appropriate amount of water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Quick Start - Back" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/2_unboxing/back_instructions.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last step in the quick start is a note on the application provide by Rise Gardens.
I'm new at hydroponics, so I'm looking forward to using this for the first few growing
cycles. I'm also hoping that I learn something about how much nutrient solution I should
be adding, so that I don't need to be reliant on the app in the future. We'll see
how that works out. Technology is nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Nursery" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/2_unboxing/nursery.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On to the nursery! I'm going to admit, I was surprised by how small this nursery is.
I don't know what I was expecting, but it was larger. Now that I've thought about it for
more than five seconds though, this is perfect. This is a &lt;em&gt;nursery&lt;/em&gt;. It's designed to
help the plants sprout, not grow. That's what the garden is for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nursery holds twelve plant pods and has a hole for adding water. If you look closely at the
inside of the quick start guide, you'll see the nice bold warning: Never add nutrients to nursery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Plant Pod" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/2_unboxing/plant_holder.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plant pods, or net cups as the quick start calls them, clips into the nursery. They are
easy to add and remove. They are also much more solidly built than the plastic of the
nursery. I'm interested in seeing how the nursery holds up after a couple cycles of
clipping/unclipping these pods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Nutrient Sensor" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/2_unboxing/water_tester.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last thing in the first box, apart from the seeds, is the nutrient sensor and
extra batteries. Before I migrate plants from the nursery to the garden, I'll read
up on how this works. In the mean time, quickly looking at it I see that it does
pH readings and EC (electro-current) readings. As I go through a few cycles, and with
the help of the app, I'll figure out what is the correct range of values for each of these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Nutrients" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/2_unboxing/nutrients.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In boxes two and three, there were nutrients for the garden. It's not mentioned
in the quick start, but in the large instruction manual provided with the garden itself,
there are brief instructions on the difference between the two provided here. The
general idea, though, is that it helps the plants grow and produce. Obviously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-seeds"&gt;The seeds&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#the-seeds" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we get to the seeds. What will I be growing on the first round of two of plants.
With a three tier garden, and three nurseries, I have room for 36 individual. That's a
lot of vegetables all at once. I'm planning on staggering these in 3-4 week batches. That
what I don't get 40 tomatoes all at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the boxes, I received the same plants for each, plus an extra box of chamomile in
boxes two and three. That's eight pods. I'm not sure what I'm going to do with that
much chamomile, but I'll figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="salad-mix"&gt;Salad Mix&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#salad-mix" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Salad Mix" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/2_unboxing/salad_mix.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In each large box, I received two salad mix boxes. Each of these contains&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 pod of Red Oak lettuce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 pod of butter lettuce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 pod of dragoon romain lettuce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 pod of astro arugula&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll have lettuce forever. Excellent. These also grow relatively quickly, so I'll
be able to cycle through these consistently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="variety-pack"&gt;Variety Pack&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#variety-pack" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Variety Pack" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/2_unboxing/variety_pack.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I received a variety pack in each large box. This pack contains&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 pod of little bing tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 pod of dwarf blue kale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 pod of swiss chard bright lights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 pod of fresh bites orange peppers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="basil"&gt;Basil&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#basil" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Basil" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/2_unboxing/basil.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last package of seeds was four pods of basil, in each large package. I'm not sure
what I'm going to do with twelve basil pods, but again, I'll figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="plant-pod"&gt;Plant Pod&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#plant-pod" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Plant Pod" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/2_unboxing/plant_pod.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plant seed pods fit nicely into the net cups. There are a couple seeds in
each pod.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#summary" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nurseries look easy enough to use. Select the plants I want, stick the seed pods
into a net cup and add water. Wait a week or two for sprouts and then transfer to the
garden until harvest time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My only complaint about this entire round of unboxing is rather minor. Honestly, it
wouldn't even be a complaint, if I hadn't received the variety packs of seeds. If, instead
I'd gotten just single pods of lettuce or tomato or peppers, I wouldn't have thought
of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My complaint is that I have twelve pods of basil. I don't use that much basil. A variety
pack of herbs would have been awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, as I said, very minor complaint. I will figure out what to do with some fresh basil.
I have family members that will probably be happy to get some.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, the nurseries look good. The seeds look good. The tiny little gardener in
me is ready to see if I can grow something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With another unboxing complete, I am ready to start assembling the garden. My next post
will cover &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-garden-assembly.html"&gt;assembly of the garden&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="review"></category><category term="garden"></category><category term="hydroponics"></category></entry><entry><title>Unboxing and reviewing the new indoor Rise Gardens hydroponic garden</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-gardens-unboxing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-04-22T10:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-10-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Andy Wegner</name></author><id>tag:andrewwegner.com,2020-04-22:/rise-gardens-unboxing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The garden has arrived! Time to open it up and see how it looks.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#introduction" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next several posts, I'm going to provide my review of the family's new
indoor garden. At the point this article is being written, it's been unboxed, assembled
and we've planted the first round of seeds. I anticipate by the time I'm done with this series,
I'll have some plants migrated from the nursery to the garden itself. Once I reach the point of
harvest, I'll provide a follow up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that, let's begin my review of the new Rise Gardens farm!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update&lt;/em&gt;: For the final summary, please read my &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-garden-final-review.html"&gt;final review&lt;/a&gt;. I encourage you to read
the whole series because I cover individual aspects of the product, but if you are just looking for the
final review, you can jump right to that &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/rise-garden-final-review.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most of last year, I had my mind set that I wanted a small indoor garden. We used to have
an outdoor garden, but it never really did that well. This was due to both the soil and the wildlife.
Last summer and fall, I went and forth between building an internal garden and buying one and
never really settled on one. During the winter, I found &lt;a href="https://risegardens.com/"&gt;Rise Gardens&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a hydroponic garden, which is exactly what I wanted. I don't want soil everywhere
and I'd prefer something self contained. Plus, I was secretly hoping the kids would find it
exciting to watch vegetables grow and then harvest and eat them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortly before the entire world shut down due to COVID-19, I ordered a garden. It was scheduled to ship in
mid-February. Sadly, it did not. The shipping date arrived and an email notice was sent saying that shipping
had been delayed approximately a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mid-March showed up and again, no garden. This time, though, I was promised additional nurseries and some
plant nutrients for waiting patiently. I had no major complaints and with the world slowly isolating
itself, we were figuring out what was going on. The delay was not a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then came mid-April. Another email and another shipping delay. However, the nurseries, seeds and nutrients
would ship on time with the garden being delayed a week. As the email said, the nurseries showed
and a week later so did the garden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The delays were unfortunate. But, I really have no major complaints. Rise Gardens was very communicative
about the delays and the causes. A global pandemic will screw with your supply chain and logistics capabilities.
Plus, the nurseries were nice. I'll cover those in a later article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I appreciate the level of communication that I've seen so far. I hope that continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-unboxing"&gt;The Unboxing&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#the-unboxing" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="boxes"&gt;Boxes&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#boxes" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ordered the triple level garden. According to the specifications, that means it's 66 inches tall and weights 106 pounds.
It showed up in three boxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Garden Boxes" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/1_unboxing/garden_boxes.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two boxes on the left are the second and third levels of the garden. The big box is the main garden, the water basin,
and the electronic brains of the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="extensions"&gt;Extensions&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#extensions" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started by opening the smaller boxes. Each extension comes with a planter tray, a grow light for the level below, some
tray covers for the plants, wooden extensions to add to the main garden, and some assembly hardware (screws).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Extension 1" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/1_unboxing/tray_covers_extension_tidy.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this picture, the tray the water will sit in is the black tray. If you look closely, you see that it is in a white tray.
This is the light cover for the lower level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Extension 2" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/1_unboxing/tray_covers_extension_untidy.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second extension has the same hardware as the first. The difference is, this one didn't show up as nicely packaged. It
looks like tape holdig the tray covers in place came loose in shipping and allowed everything to slide around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Extension Brackets" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/1_unboxing/extension_brackets.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These brackets are nice. They have a spot to hide the wire used to plug in the lights, seem solidly made and (spoiler)
fit together correctly when assembling the levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Grow Lights" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/1_unboxing/level_lights.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each level of the garden has a set of grow lights. These are two LED panels. The light tray also holds the plastic
water tray of the level above. The two holes you see at the top of this light panel are wher the plumbing passes through
to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="main-garden"&gt;Main Garden&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#main-garden" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Big Garden Box" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/1_unboxing/garden_box_open.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The large garden box contains three big items inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first item is the metal shelving unit. When assembled, this shelf will hold the water basin inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Garden Shelf" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/1_unboxing/bottom_shelf_water_tray.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This shelf has two doors. On the outside are five LED lights which are used to indicate the water level
of the basic. There is also a button that controls the LED lights. This button cycles through full intensity, half
intensity and off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Water Basin" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/1_unboxing/water_tray.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The marks on the water basic coorespond to the lights on the exterior of the shelving unit. There are five blue
water level marks and five LEDs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Water Pump" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/1_unboxing/water_pump.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tucked inside the water basin is the water pump. This hangs from the side of the basic and is submerged into the
water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Watering Can" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/1_unboxing/watering_can.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rise Gardens provides a watering can. This is useful for filling the trays as well as the basin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Antenna" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/1_unboxing/antenna_smudged.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the side of the shelf unit is a spot to screw in the little antenna. This allows the control board to
connect to the local wireless network. In doing so, you can connect your phone to the garden and receive
updates about water levels as well as help in planning out your garden and when nutrients should be added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My antenna showed up looking rather smudged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Control Board" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/1_unboxing/control_board.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The control board is already set up and attached to the internal side of the shelf unit. I am not sure what the
A and B ports are used for and don't recall reading about them in the manual, but the rest of the ports are
pretty easy to figure out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Main Garden Tray" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/1_unboxing/tray.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much like the extensions mentioned above, the main garden comes with the first tray of the system. Also like
one of the extensions mentioned above, the internal parts of this tray came loose and shifted during
transportation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Loose Screws" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/1_unboxing/tray_hardware_untidy.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The assembly hardware and brick portion of the power supply slide all over. Some of the screws got wedged between the
tray and the cardboard packaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this also seems to have scratched the tray a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Top Lights" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/garden/1_unboxing/top_light_brackets.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last part of the packaging is the top light and brackets. The brackets here re the legs that attach to
the shelf and hold it off the ground. The light will be installed above the top level of plants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#summary" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll provide a more concise break down of pros and cons in a later article, so that you don't need to read each
individual one. For now though, let's talk about what I thought while unboxing everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I noticed was that Rise Gardens provides printed instructions. This is something I'd been worried about.
I had found their &lt;a href="https://support.risegardens.com/hc/en-us/articles/360039901993-Garden-Assembly-Instructions"&gt;assembly instructions&lt;/a&gt; on their web site and I was concerned that's what I've had to use to assemble
the garden. The included instructors are the same as those on the website, but I like the tangible instructions to needing
my phone near by during assembly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second thing I noticed, both during this unboxing and while unboxing the nurseries is that Rise Gardens loves their packaging
tape. Box seams are fully covered. Tape is not something they are concerned about...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...on the outside boxes. Internally though, the lack of tape or using cheap masking tape, caused interal components to break free
and slide all over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hardware feels very high quality. I don't feel like I'm going to snap these wooden legs or brackets when I put weight on them. The
control board, and the electronics in general, appear very well assembled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, despite some packaging annoyances, I'm looking forward to assembling this thing over the coming day. Next up, though, is
&lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/nursery-unboxing.html"&gt;unpacking my first round of seeds and the nurseries&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="review"></category><category term="garden"></category><category term="hydroponics"></category></entry><entry><title>Review of Ultimate AWS Certified Developer Associate 2019 course</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/aws-certified-developer-review.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-23T10:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-12-23T10:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Andy Wegner</name></author><id>tag:andrewwegner.com,2019-12-23:/aws-certified-developer-review.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My review of the Ultimate AWS Certified Developer Associate course.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#introduction" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my personal and professional goals for 2019 was to get a certification of some kind. That's a
fairly broad requirement with no real reasoning behind it. I wanted to learn something and I wanted it
to be helpful at work. As the year rapidly entered the last few months, I realized I not done anything
to reach the goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a brief talk with my management, it was decided that I should get an AWS certification. It'd help
the company out with some work we are doing to become an AWS partner, and I'd get a certification that would
be useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a read goal, I set out to learn something. I started by finding &lt;a href="https://www.udemy.com/course/aws-certified-developer-associate-dva-c01/"&gt;Ultimate AWS Certified Developer Associate 2019&lt;/a&gt;
on Udemy. At the time I'm posting this entry, the course has been updated to be useful for 2020. It's always a good sign
that the creator is continuously updating their materials. This course was created by Stephane Maarek, who also
holds the certification that is being taught about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="course-overview"&gt;Course Overview&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#course-overview" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course is a 19 hour overview of most of AWS. At first I thought that length was excessive, but it turns out
that 19 hours isn't enough. This course is focused only on the AWS products that you need to know for the DVA-C01
certification. There is...a lot to know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The materials go through how to use AWS's free tier for almost all of the work needed for the course. The very few
areas that can't utilize the free tier are explicitly called out, so you don't end up with surprise AWS bills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend you set aside the time to go through this course and the practice tests. Then, I recommend
that you do it again. AWS has a &lt;em&gt;ton&lt;/em&gt; of services with three letter names. You need to know how those work
and interact with one another. You need to know how to troubleshoot them, set them up, and scale them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One pass through this course wasn't enough for me. I don't blame the instructor though. I blame the expansiveness of
the test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The practice questions were very similar to what questions looked like on the real exam. The concepts that were
covered were helpful in answering a few others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="conclusion"&gt;Conclusion&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#conclusion" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If (when?) I go for the next level of certifications in Amazon, I'll be looking for more courses from this creator.
The course is very well built, very hands on, and obviously updated to stay relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In November, I took my exam and passed on the first try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have other professional goals for next year, but if I decide to go for another AWS certification, I'll
be looking for another course by Stephane Maarek.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ude.my/UC-CAXZ5N6F"&gt;&lt;img alt="Ultimate AWS Certified Developer Associate 2019" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/udemy-aws-developer-certification.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="AWS Certified Developer - J2WR9QVC314Q1FSY" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/aws_certified_developer.png"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="review"></category><category term="technical"></category><category term="learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Review of Travis CI Tutorial Udemy course</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/travis-ci-tutorial-review.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-09T14:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-07-09T14:30:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Andy Wegner</name></author><id>tag:andrewwegner.com,2019-07-09:/travis-ci-tutorial-review.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My review of the Travis CI Tutorial course on Udemy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#introduction" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've written about Travis CI before. I've reported a bug that makes it fairly easy
to see &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/travisci-insecure-environment-variables.html"&gt;environment variables in Travis CI&lt;/a&gt; or even unintentionally transfer
them if you transfer your repository. I &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/autobuild-pelican-blog.html"&gt;build this blog using Travis CI&lt;/a&gt;. I've
&lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/how-i-set-up-openshift-travisci-and-flask.html"&gt;used Travis CI to set up an OpenShift application&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/can-a-machine-be-taught-to-flag-spam-automatically.html"&gt;SmokeDetector&lt;/a&gt; uses it to 
manage it's blacklists. In short, I have experience with Travis CI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was surprised when I saw a course being offered for free recently on Udemy that
deals with Travis CI. Since it was free and only a couple hours long, I figured I'd
give it a shot. I enrolled in the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my review of &lt;a href="https://www.udemy.com/travis-ci-tutorial/"&gt;Travis CI Tutorial&lt;/a&gt; by Vaga Notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="course"&gt;Course&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#course" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course starts with no instructor introduction, no explanation of what
the course is about, or goals for the course. If you don't know what Travis CI is,
don't expect to learn that here. You are expected to know what it is and what
it does. Honestly, you should probably have used it before too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All coding done for this course is gone in the GitHub web editor. This bothered
me initially, but after thinking about it, not so much. Most of the "real code"
needed for this course is simply editing the &lt;code&gt;.travis.yml&lt;/code&gt; file and the instructor
saves a lot of time by &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; dealing with git and GitHub more than necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I think that is going to be the last good thing I have to say
about this course. The rest can be summed up with one word: Inconsistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sound is inconsistent. From one lesson to another, the instructor goes from
being whisper quiet at highest volume to so loud it hurts. The microphone being
used picks up static and most annoyingly, the instructor keeps coughing into the
mic. Sound &lt;em&gt;within&lt;/em&gt; a lesson is also inconsistent. In one lesson - Lesson 13 "Build Stages" -
it went from quiet to loud and back multiple times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Testing of the course material was inconsistent. The instructor recording their
videos an hour after they had done it the first time, in some cases. This
short time between doing it the first time and recording it for the tutorial
is seen in how the instructor handles unexpected delays and failing builds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation is inconsistent. On several videos, the instructor obviously
spent time making an intro and outro for the lecture. It's a few second animation
and sound effect that encapsulates the lesson. On others, they jump right into the
material or awkwardly end the lesson. If the instructor had spent more time
giving the course a unified look and feel through the entire course, it'd come
across as more polished. Instead, it looks like it was thrown together haphazardly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which brings me to the content. This is also inconsistent. There are points where
the instructor didn't have a script at worse and only high level bullet points
at best. They mumble their way through an explanation or series of interface
options. They live code - with typos - their way through set up. They navigate to
GitHub using Google Search, but accidentally click to quickly and get a previous
search result (that could have been embarrassing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with the live coded examples and an after thought of an explanation of
what each step means, there is very bad advice given in some locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first example of this is setting up environment variables (see my post
on &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/travisci-insecure-environment-variables.html"&gt;Travis CI environment variables&lt;/a&gt;). While setting up the GitHub token, so
that Travis can deploy GitHub Pages, the advice given is to "just give it all
the access". NO! NO NO NO NO NO! NO!. Especially when combined with the next
step they took, which isn't even described.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The instructor moves over to Travis CI from GitHub to put in the environment variable.
They put in the name of the variable and the value. Then they change the "Display
this value in build log" from the default "Off" to "On" &lt;em&gt;and don't say why&lt;/em&gt;!.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moments later a build is pushed, the Travis CI log is shown, and there is the
GitHub token that had "all the access" displayed in the build log. Anyone can
come along and use that token to do anything to your GitHub repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="final-thoughts"&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#final-thoughts" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course is now listed for $20. It's not worth it. Go find something on YouTube,
look at another repository that is already using Travis CI or Google for an example.
Any of those options are going to be more useful to you - and more consistent - than
this course. With the bad sound, half finished video introductions, and horrible
advice on token generation the only thing you'll be doing if you take this course is
play with your volume constantly and learn the wrong way to set up environment variables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course feels like it was recorded while the instructor was home sick with a
minor cold and got bored with their video editing software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ude.my/UC-IJRCAV24"&gt;&lt;img alt="Software Testing Masterclass (2019) - From Notice to Expert" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/udemy-travis-ci.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="review"></category><category term="technical"></category><category term="learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Review of Software Testing Masterclass (2019) - From Notice to Expert Udemy course</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/software-testing-masterclass.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-14T15:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-05-14T15:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Andy Wegner</name></author><id>tag:andrewwegner.com,2019-05-14:/software-testing-masterclass.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My review of the Software Testing Masterclass course on Udemy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#introduction" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do QA work for my job and love learning new things, techniques or ways of doing
my job better. The &lt;a href="https://ude.my/UC-1F1K67C9"&gt;Software Testing Masterclass (2019) - From Novice to Expert&lt;/a&gt;
caught my eye during one of Udemy's many sales. This course is only five hours long
so I figured it'd be a quick overview (and I'd be able to skip of the 'novice') part
of the course. It was created by Ozan İlhan. Their Udemy biograph says they
have been a professional software tester for the last 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="course"&gt;Course&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#course" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First things first, English is not the instructor's first language. In most of the
course this is not a problem, but be aware that there are some grammatical things
that may throw a native speaker. Normally, I wouldn't count this against the
instructor, but they specifically call out in the course description:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All videos have hand edited subtitles. We spent many hours to correct all the subtitles to help you to have a smooth learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, those subtitles are exactly what was said, so the grammar issues
are even more glaring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The "high-quality sound" that boasted about in the course description doesn't
seem accurate. Sound from one lesson to the next varies wildly. In one lesson
it is difficult to hear the instructor and in the next they are super loud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK, on to the actual content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt this course did not take the "to Expert" part of the name to heart. Much
of the content was power point slides being read to the student. The "Novice"
portion of the course was laying a groundwork for students to understand the
different types of testing, software development life cycle, how to report bugs,
and how to build test cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The instructor provided a template for bug reporting and test case checklists. I
cringe a little bit because these are Excel documents, but I've worked in the
corporate world and Excel is the hammer used to pound every nail. I've seen and used
templates that look very similar. It's not flashy or "an app", but it is what's
used "in the real world", even if I hated using it at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the "Expert" part of the course is labeled "Advance Testing Concepts",
which covers different types of tests in more detail. This covers, black box testing,
smoke and sanity testing, reggression testing, risk based testing and a few others.
Unfortunately, this is presented as Power Point slides again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last real content in the course is covering how to sign up for various
things like GitHub, JIRA, TestRail and TestLodge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the course ends with what feels like a bunch of advertisements for
freelance testing services. There are very brief overviews of uTest, Testlio,
and BugFinders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="final-thoughts"&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#final-thoughts" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I am disappointed in this course. I was really hoping the "Expert" part
covered a bit more or even new methods. Unfortunately, everything here I've heard
of and used at one point or another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I'm really disappointed that so much of the course was being read
a Power Point presentation. I was hoping to see some testing frameworks in action
to compare/contrast the benefits of one over the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the over use of Power Point though, and the last part of the course feeling
like plugs for various services, I can't recommend this course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ude.my/UC-1F1K67C9"&gt;&lt;img alt="Software Testing Masterclass (2019) - From Notice to Expert" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/udemy-testing-masterclass.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="review"></category><category term="technical"></category><category term="learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Review of Sanic - An Asynchronous Web Framework for Pythonistas Udemy course</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/sanic-webframework-review.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-01-23T10:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-01-23T10:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Andy Wegner</name></author><id>tag:andrewwegner.com,2019-01-23:/sanic-webframework-review.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My review of the Sanic Web Framework fro Pythonistas course on Udemy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#introduction" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At work we are starting to write version 2 of our API. As part of this new version, we're migrating from PHP to Python (hooray!). There are various technical
reasons for this, but I am excited. My technical skills are much (&lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt;) better in Python. Part of this migration involved decided the framework we'd be using
and after several internal discussions, we settled on &lt;a href="https://sanic.readthedocs.io/en/latest/"&gt;Sanic&lt;/a&gt;. The first line of the documentation reads:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sanic is a Flask-like Python 3.5+ web server that’s written to go fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great! I used Flask at my previous job. To be clear, Sanic is not &lt;em&gt;based on&lt;/em&gt; Flask, but it's API is &lt;em&gt;Flask-like&lt;/em&gt;. Good enjoy to start with. With the framework
set, and previous experience with a similar framework, I wanted to go through how Sanic works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I turned to Udemy and the &lt;a href="https://www.udemy.com/sanic-an-asynchronous-web-framework-for-pythonistas/"&gt;Sanic - an asynchronous web framework for Pythonistas&lt;/a&gt; course, created by Szabó Dániel Ernő.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="course"&gt;Course&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#course" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course is roughly two hours long and consists of 20 tutorial videos. Each one is less than 10 minutes long. It covers a wide range of features available in
Sanic. The instructor made their code available on &lt;a href="https://github.com/r3ap3rpy/sanic-web-framework"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. I never actually used the GitHub repository though. Instead, I followed along with the brief
tutorials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, this speaks to the instructor's ability to keep the lessons and code short and simple yet effectively show how a single feature works. By making the
code easy enough to type and follow along, the lesson was more effective because I was &lt;em&gt;doing&lt;/em&gt; instead of just reading code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first few lessons are a little rough, because the recordings stutter like the machine that was doing the recording wasn't powerful enough. After 5-6 lessons
this clears up. It's a minor thing but I do feel it's something that should have been fixed before the course was posted. One other annoyance was that each
lesson contains the same boiler plate code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="codehilight code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;sanic&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;app&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;sanic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Sanic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="vm"&gt;__name__&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;"__main__"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;app&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;run&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;host&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"localhost"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;port&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;8000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lesson code will then go after the &lt;code&gt;app&lt;/code&gt; variable is defined. The problem with this boiler plate code is that the instructor types it out every single lesson.
Again, this is minor and it makes each lesson self contained, but I think having this code already written and adding in the important, lesson specific code,
would have made the lesson more succinct. It also would have prevented a few typos that the instructor made and had to spend time correcting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="thoughts-on-the-lessons"&gt;Thoughts on the lessons&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#thoughts-on-the-lessons" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lessons themselves were effective at teaching a single Sanic feature. Some were a little short and almost all of them lacked any complexity you'd find in
a real application, but they were quick ways to show how a feature worked and didn't spend a lot of time doing more than that. Lessons covered a variety of
things you'd expect a web framework to handle:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Request Parameters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aliases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Listeners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Middleware&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cookies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Streaming files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Class methodology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blueprints&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Request Types&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Error handling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ironically, in the error handling lesson, the instructor had an error in their code. This is great, because it helps to see how to troubleshoot errors that Sanic
can throw. My issue is that the instructor left the time where he's looking at another monitor (probably reading documentation) in the video. I feel this time
could have been removed and the troubleshooting steps still been effectively shown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="final-thoughts"&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#final-thoughts" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I was happy with this course. It's about two hours long and does a good job of showing various aspects of Sanic. I don't recall ever being pointed
to the documentation, which is a little surprising, but it was easy enough to find. The course provides a good foundation of knowing what Sanic can handle. As
of the time of this post, Udemy says there have been ten students that signed up for the course. That is low and the lack of Q&amp;amp;A is also a bit concerning. I
don't know how responsive the instructor is to student questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a few hours (and dollars, during a Udemy sale) to spare and wish to learn some basics about Sanic, this is a good course to take. If not, the
&lt;a href="https://github.com/r3ap3rpy/sanic-web-framework"&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt; contains all of the lessons you go over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ude.my/UC-LYP0VLF7"&gt;&lt;img alt="Sanic - An Asynchronous Web Framework for Pythonistas Completion" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/udemy-sanic.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="review"></category><category term="technical"></category><category term="learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Review of Udemy's Docker Swarm: Beginner + Advanced</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/docker-swarm-beginner-advanced.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-31T15:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-10-31T15:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Andy Wegner</name></author><id>tag:andrewwegner.com,2018-10-31:/docker-swarm-beginner-advanced.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My review of the Docker Swarm: Beginner + Advanced&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#introduction" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently found short two courses about Docker on Udemy there were listed as free by the author as they get ready to update the course. This is a review of &lt;a href="https://www.udemy.com/docker-swarm-from-beginner-to-advanced-with-docker-cluster-hosting/"&gt;Docker Swarm: Beginner + Advanced&lt;/a&gt; by Luke Angel. This is the second course I've reviewed by this author. The previous course was reviewed &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/docker-essentials-course.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a very basic idea of what the container/microservice architecture is designed to solve. I've never used it professionally or on personal projects. My experience is limited to reading articles about technologies such as Docker or Kubernetes and thinking that I'd like to try those out at some point in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="course"&gt;Course&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#course" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is another hour long course and promises "foundational knowledge" by the end of the course. I disagree with this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course starts with a lecture that is essentially an ad (almost in the form of a TV episode trailer) for the course. There are duplicate lectures, which seems to be a recurring problem based on the same issue in the previous course. Another problem that has carried over from the previous course is audio issues and inconsistencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a beginner course, despite the name. The author assumes knowledge of Docker and does not explain concepts when the "demo" starts. Speaking of the "demo", this isn't a true demonstration of the product. Instead, the author provides a ZIP file of commands that are run and outputs of those commands. In the lectures, a few elements of the output are highlighted and explained. I didn't find this to be a useful demonstration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="final-thoughts"&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#final-thoughts" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a course that is several years old. It is not well put together, with multiple lectures being duplicated. Sound issues plague the presentation throughout the hour. These are all similar complaints to the &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/docker-essentials-course.html"&gt;previous course&lt;/a&gt;. This course also includes a demonstration, that is really just looking at the output of an attached text file. For a demonstration, I was expecting to be able to follow along, as as this is "Beginner + Advanced", I was expecting some kind of instructions on how to set up my environment. There is none.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't recommend this course (or the &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/docker-essentials-course.html"&gt;previous one&lt;/a&gt;) because of how little "useful" content is fit into these two hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ude.my/UC-X9SRS3MO"&gt;&lt;img alt="Completion Award" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/udemy-docker-swarm-beginner-to-advanced.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="review"></category><category term="technical"></category><category term="learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Review of Udemy's Docker and Containers: The Essentials</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/docker-essentials-course.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-29T09:45:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-10-29T09:45:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Andy Wegner</name></author><id>tag:andrewwegner.com,2018-10-29:/docker-essentials-course.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My review of the Docker and Containers: The Essentials&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#introduction" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently found short two courses about Docker on Udemy there were listed as free by the author as they get ready to update the course. This is a review of &lt;a href="https://www.udemy.com/docker-and-containers-the-essentials/"&gt;Docker and Containers: The Essentials&lt;/a&gt; by Luke Angel. There is a third free Docker course by the same author as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a very basic idea of what the container/microservice architecture is designed to solve. I've never used it professionally or on personal projects. My experience is limited to reading articles about technologies such as Docker or Kubernetes and thinking that I'd like to try those out at some point in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="course"&gt;Course&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#course" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course is a one hour, very high level, overview of what containers are. The course description mentions that there won't be detailed developer examples, and this is true. My issue with the course is that it is to high level. This course is not for anyone with even a tiny idea of what a container is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author has basically created an hour long, narrated Power Point presentation. Even worse, there are at least two instances of lecture that are duplicated (and are pointed out in the community feedback and Q&amp;amp;A section). The narration is obviously edited from multiple microphones and the sound consistency is uneven. The author also spends lectures typing on their keyboard while talking. This is loud and distracting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Motivational speaking makes it into one of the final lectures, explaining that we are winners for being on the right track by studying Docker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="final-thoughts"&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#final-thoughts" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a course that is several years old. It is not well put together, with multiple lectures being duplicated. Sound issues plague the presentation throughout the hour. The content of the course is accurate - as of a few years ago - but has areas that are outdated at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know how long the author is spending on updating their courses, but there is a lot that needs to be done in just this one hour course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ude.my/UC-WEQ6PT39"&gt;&lt;img alt="Completion Award" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/udemy-docker-containers-essentials.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="review"></category><category term="technical"></category><category term="learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Review of Udemy's renamed The 2018 Git Complete: 45 minute crash course using Angular.</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/git-45-minute-crash-course.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-01T09:45:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-10-01T09:45:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Andy Wegner</name></author><id>tag:andrewwegner.com,2018-10-01:/git-45-minute-crash-course.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My review of the The 2018 Git Complete: 45 minute crash course using Angular.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#introduction" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use Git extensively in both my personal and professional work. I've set up &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/installing-gitlab.html"&gt;GitLab&lt;/a&gt; for my personal work. I know enough about Git to be effective in a small environment with a handful of developers. I found a 30 minute crash course about Git on Udemy and decided to take it with the goal of learning a little bit more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course I found was &lt;a href="https://www.udemy.com/git-complete-the-30-minute-crash-course-to-learning-git/"&gt;The 30 minute crash course to learning GIT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.udemy.com/git-complete-the-30-minute-crash-course-to-learning-git/"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt; by Ricardo Morales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spoiler&lt;/em&gt;: I rated this course poorly on Udemy and since that rating, the course name has been changed to "The 2018 Git Complete: 45 minute Crash Course using Angular". The course has been updated slightly to add 15 more minutes of content since I completed the course. I have watched those as well and have not changed my rating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="course"&gt;Course&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#course" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I took this course it was definitely incomplete. The very first lesson starts with "In our previous lecture...". Obviously, as the first lecture, there isn't a previous one. The 15 minutes of new content does add a few introduction lectures before this, so it's not as jarring, but the order of lectures is still out of order. There are next instances of "In the next lecture I'll cover..." and then the next lecture is something else, or "In the last lecture we talked about..." and the mentioned topic was a few lectures ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course is a very quick run down of common Git commands. Very quick. Most lessons are under a minute in length. What this means is that there is almost no explanation about the command you're about to learn. In most of the lectures, it's a quick reading of the command's "help" sentence, then typing the command in a terminal window to show the syntax. Unfortunately, there isn't an over all project and the order of the lectures is out of order, so it's difficult to see how a particular command actually works since there isn't any set up done ahead of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One example of how this is poorly demonstrated is in the lecture on renaming a file. The example uses &lt;code&gt;mv&lt;/code&gt; to rename a file, talks about how it's been renamed, and then uses &lt;code&gt;mv&lt;/code&gt; to rename it back to the original name to that there "won't be problems with Git." The entire point of the lecture is to show how this should be accomplished and this lecture misses it's mark entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another example is in the lessons on handling merge conflicts. This is an important topic because conflicts need to be handled when multiple developers are working on the same thing. The lecture on handling these though talks about the theory of handling it but doesn't provide a demo. The same thing is done in the topic on rebasing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minute long lectures are not a good format. The lessons are rushed to the point where there is almost no content. Reading the "help" sentence and then showing the syntax doesn't make this a crash course. It makes it an audio/visual help document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="final-thoughts"&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#final-thoughts" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you know anything about Git, avoid this course. If you don't know anything about Git, I'd avoid it too, unless you prefer listening to help documents instead of reading them. There isn't any novel content here. Examples are lacking, at best. Lectures are out of order and when I took it, missing entirely. The newly renamed course to include "using Angular" is incredibly misleading. Angular is used only to generate a project that can be committed to Git. Nothing done here uses Angular other than generating that project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you know anything about Git, there is nothing here you don't know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The completion award below reflects the name of the course before it was renamed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ude.my/UC-H4EVPTH5"&gt;&lt;img alt="Completion Award" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/udemy-git-crash-course.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="review"></category><category term="technical"></category><category term="learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Review of Udemy's Learn DaVinci Resolve 15 from scratch</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/learn-davinci-resolve-15-from-scratch.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-21T09:45:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-09-21T09:45:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Andy Wegner</name></author><id>tag:andrewwegner.com,2018-09-21:/learn-davinci-resolve-15-from-scratch.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My review of the Learn DaVinci Resolve 15 from scratch course on Udemy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#introduction" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been a while since I've done a course review. I wanted to try something new in an area that seems interesting, but I'm not sure if I want to do anything with it hobby-wise. &lt;a href="https://www.udemy.com/davinci-resolve-15-from-scratch/"&gt;Learn DaVinci Resolve 15 from scratch&lt;/a&gt; caught my attention, and I found a coupon code that allowed me to take the course for free. Video editting sounds interesting and I always have the "do something with family videos" on my very distant TODO list. The course is two and a half hours long and it seems to be a basic class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.blackmagicdesign.com/products/davinciresolve/"&gt;DaVinci Resolve&lt;/a&gt; is a very powerful, professional piece video editing software. The free version has everything I'd ever need for home use or even YouTube content. The paid version adds in multi-user collaboration features, additional 3D tools and new Resolve FX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="course"&gt;Course&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#course" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course focuses heavily on learning the &lt;em&gt;interface&lt;/em&gt; of DaVinci Resolve. There are a few basic tutorials and the author promises more in the future. This isn't exactly what I was expecting with a course description that includes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn how to use DaVinci Resolve to create beautiful and stunning videos for the world to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, it does provide a good overview of each of the tabs in DaVinci Resolve. The explanation of what each tab is used for and the very basic examples of how to use each give users an idea of how powerful DaVinci Resolve can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="thoughts-on-the-lessons"&gt;Thoughts on the lessons&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#thoughts-on-the-lessons" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an overview of the interface for DaVinci Resolve, this course is good. As a "learn from scratch" course, the interface overview quickly shows that two and a half hours isn't enough time to learn the software beyond the very basics. The title is a bit misleading and as someone who didn't know anything about DaVinci Resolve and only took this course because of a potentially budding hobby, I was hoping for more than a two hour tutorial on where to click in the interface to do the basics. Alas, my ignorance of the topic meant I wasn't able to judge the course accurately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had several nit-picks with the content too. For one, I was immediately turned off to the course creator when they begged in the first lecture to not give them bad reviews. That isn't the type of thing I expect from someone who's put time and effort into creating the course. I was worried when this was done, but it turned out to be better than the begging implied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My second complaint is about how the content is presented. This is a course on &lt;em&gt;video editting&lt;/em&gt;. I expect a certain amount of care to be put into the presentation of such a topic, but the course wasn't well paced. There are very abrupt endings to several lectures. There are other lectures that have long periods of silence at the end. There are also more than a few occasions where the audio and video seem to be out of sync. You never see the instructor, but when they are presenting a new tab and say something like "Click on this tab" and then the mouse doesn't move to the tab for a few seconds it makes it hard to follow along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My final complaint is how incomplete the course is. There is one five second lecture that is just "This lecture will be uploaded very soon". The last bonus lecutre ends with "See you at the next lecture", but there are no more lectures. I realize the course was released this month, but it's incomplete. The full price of the course is $80. I expect more to be completed for that price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a good overview of the DaVinci Resolve environment. I understand what each tab is and how I can use them for basic edits. I feel comfortable enough to make a very simple video with some home videos now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="final-thoughts"&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#final-thoughts" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are paying for the course, you should avoid it for a while. It's not complete. There is no guarantee that additional lectures will be added and the promise of "more to come" isn't worth the full price. If you are looking for an overview of the most important buttons in DaVinci Resolve, this is a good course. If you are looking for details on what every button or menu option is going to do, this course doesn't cover that. Finally, if you are really looking to "learn DaVinci Resolve" and not "learn the DaVinci Resolve interface", this isn't the best course either. There are some tutorials here, but they are not the majority of content. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ude.my/UC-SMH6Q3ET"&gt;&lt;img alt="Completion Award" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/udemy-learn-davinci-resolve-15-from-scratch.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="review"></category><category term="technical"></category><category term="learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Review of Udemy's Django Course from Basics to Advance</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/django-course-basic-to-advance.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-02-20T22:45:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-02-20T22:45:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Andy Wegner</name></author><id>tag:andrewwegner.com,2018-02-20:/django-course-basic-to-advance.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My review of the Django Course from Basics to Advance course on Udemy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#introduction" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/new-house-server.html"&gt;new server&lt;/a&gt; coming along nicely, I wanted to take a quick refresher on Django. Last summer I went through another &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/django-fullstack-bootcamp-course-review.html"&gt;Django course&lt;/a&gt;. That
was a decent course. I didn't need anything that intensive or that focused on the non-Django portions though. I have a couple plans for web control panels
that will help me manage the aspects of the new server I care most about. I decided to take a look at &lt;a href="https://www.udemy.com/django-course-from-basics-to-advance/"&gt;Django Course from Basics to Advance&lt;/a&gt; by Bucky Roberts.
It is billed as a five hour course and seemed to hit major aspects of the framework. It was released in January 2018, so it was brand new at the time I signed up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoiler alert: &lt;em&gt;Avoid this course&lt;/em&gt;. It's a waste of money. The bad grammar in the title should have been the red flag that made me avoid it. Unfortunately, that was
only the start of my issues with the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="thoughts-on-the-course"&gt;Thoughts on the course&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#thoughts-on-the-course" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Literally ten seconds into the first lecture: "If you guys were wondering what the F Django is, it's not a movie, well it is a movie." It only goes
down hill from there. A few complaints:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A majority of the lectures start with "Alright Hauses"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Think of [Django] like PHP, if you guys are fuzzy on it, but cooler."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lecture 3 includes a rant about what an "app" is and how everyone is developing "apps" now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In lecture 10, the instructor starts with a rant about an overweight airline passenger sitting next to them on a plane&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Insults and mocking of front end developers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One of the lectures ends with "To be honest, my mom keeps texting me and it's kind of annoying."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Another lecture is interrupted with this train of thought: "There is a dog barking outside. It's annoying me."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, one lecture ends with "Thank you guys for watching. Don't forget to subscribe!"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a YouTube channel. The instructor uploaded their YouTube channel to Udemy. Not only that, they uploaded two year old tutorial videos. It's not
even current!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are technical issues with the course too:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The instructor is using Django 1.9. There is three years out of date at this point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installation instructions tell users to use administration or &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt; rights for all Python libraries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installation instructions are done using &lt;code&gt;easy_install&lt;/code&gt; not &lt;code&gt;pip&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;code&gt;urls.py&lt;/code&gt; files that define URL routes, there are lines that look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="codehilight code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;url(r'^admin/', admin.site.urls)
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The instructor attempts to describe the &lt;code&gt;r&lt;/code&gt; in front of &lt;code&gt;'^admin/'&lt;/code&gt; by saying:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever I type "r", it means 'regular expression'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just flat wrong. &lt;code&gt;r&lt;/code&gt; indicates a &lt;a href="https://docs.python.org/3/reference/lexical_analysis.html#string-and-bytes-literals"&gt;raw string&lt;/a&gt;. From the documentation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both string and bytes literals may optionally be prefixed with a letter 'r' or 'R'; such strings are called raw strings and treat backslashes as literal characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id="final-thoughts"&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#final-thoughts" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't waste your time with this. Don't look at it. Don't think about it. This course is a YouTube channel. If you really want to watch a two year old series running a
three year old version of Django &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qgGIqRFvFFk&amp;amp;list=PL6gx4Cwl9DGBlmzzFcLgDhKTTfNLfX1IK"&gt;watch it on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;. It's not worth it. The information is outdated and wrong in many spots. The instructor uploaded this course for
a quick dollar. They didn't build this course for Udemy. They built it for YouTube and you can tell. The quality of content here is not what I've come to expect from
Udemy course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately for me, Udemy Support was very helpful when I requested a refund. I listed most of the complaints I did above and mentioned it course was just a
YouTube channel that had been uploaded to Udemy. I was issued a refund in under an hour. I also left my first public review of a course on Udemy so that other students
know they can get the same content elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Course Review" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/django-course-basics-to-advance-review-screenshot.png"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still want to find a quick refresher. I'll have to go hunting for that later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;</content><category term="review"></category><category term="technical"></category><category term="learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Review of Udemy's AWS Serverless APIs &amp; Apps - A Complete Introduction course</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/aws-serverless-apis-apps-review.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-20T11:17:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-10-20T11:17:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Andy Wegner</name></author><id>tag:andrewwegner.com,2017-10-20:/aws-serverless-apis-apps-review.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My review of the AWS Serverless APIs &amp;amp; Apps course on Udemy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#introduction" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been involved with the &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/can-a-machine-be-taught-to-flag-spam-automatically.html"&gt;SmokeDetector&lt;/a&gt; spam hunting project for several years. In that time It's grown from
a small Python script to a large combination of Python, Ruby and user scripts. The infrastructure hasn't really changed
in that time, though, and it's starting to show. SmokeDetector, the Python script, is run by multiple users so that
random network problems that kill the instance don't take the entire system off line. Arguably, the project should
work on fixing this instability, but the alternative that we came up with works too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least it did. Now this distributed way of running is starting to cause issues. Keeping each instance in sync
with one another is a very difficult problem. We've built a decent solution to this for handling spam patterns,
but we've failed to replicate this for other things like permission sets or notifications. Adding this involves
integration with GitHub and a series of new commands. It's painful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the recent discussions to solve this problem was a centralized database. That brings me to this course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://ude.my/UC-1ESFUC2V"&gt;AWS Serverless APIs &amp;amp; Apps - A Complete Introduction&lt;/a&gt; by Maximilian Schwarzmüller on Udemy
looked like a good overview for AWS lambda and DynamoDB, two solutions the SmokeDetector project was looking
into using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="thoughts-on-the-course"&gt;Thoughts on the course&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#thoughts-on-the-course" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course provides a good overview of Amazon's API Gateway, AWS Lambda and several other Amazon services. There
is a little bit of coding involved - using NodeJS - but a large majority is dedicated to working in the various Amazon
consoles. Except for one optional lecture, the entire course can be completed using Amazon's free tier. This is
great for a course and one of the factors I used to determine if I really wanted to take the course. The instructor
is very clear, throughout the course, which aspects cost additional money so that no unexpected charges show up
from Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course covers the API Gateway, AWS permissions, AWS Lambda, body mapping templates, DynamoDB, authentication with
Cognito and hosting a serverless SPA. At first glance this seems like a lot to cover in an 8 hour course. The instructor
has broken these into small digestible lectures that do a good job of introducing each new service, explaining the theory
behind each and then using the service to implement functionality into the course long project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A course long project is a good way to show how each of these Amazon services are useful to a larger project. Instead of
focusing on a small example project where it is difficult to expand the course work into the real world, a real world
project with various requirements is used. This project uses each of the services I mentioned above in a natural way.
Implementing new functionality doesn't feel forced, instead it is something that users would expect from a modern application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am very happy with this course. Everything was very well presented. The project was useful because I can easily understand
how each of the Amazon services function. I also have a good idea how the console works and how to troubleshoot problems
because of the work that was done in this course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My only complaint with regard to this course is that the video lectures are interrupted with text based lectures consisting
of more details and links to documentation. I appreciate these links and used several of them, but the interruption of the
videos to present these broke the nice flow of the lectures. Presenting these links at the end of the section, I think would be
less of an interruption. This was a minor thing, though, and doesn't take away from how much I enjoyed the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="final-thoughts"&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#final-thoughts" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel that I have a decent understanding of Amazon's services at this point. I am looking forward to applying this new
knowledge and, hopefully, improving the SmokeDetector infrastructure at the same time. I highly recommend this course
if you are thinking of migrating anything to Amazon. I feel much more comfortable about moving aspects of a project
to this new solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ude.my/UC-1ESFUC2V"&gt;&lt;img alt="AWS Serverless APIs and Apps Completion" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/udemy-aws-serverless-apis-apps.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="review"></category><category term="technical"></category><category term="learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Review of Udemy's Python and Django Full Stack Web Developer Bootcamp course</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/django-fullstack-bootcamp-course-review.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-28T06:16:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-06-28T06:16:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Andy Wegner</name></author><id>tag:andrewwegner.com,2017-06-28:/django-fullstack-bootcamp-course-review.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My review of the Python and Django Full Stack Web Developer Bootcamp course on Udemy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#introduction" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After ploughing through &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/deep-learning-prereq-numpy.html"&gt;two machine learning&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/deep-learning-prereq-linear-logistic-regression.html"&gt;prerequisite courses&lt;/a&gt;, I wanted to have a change in content for the next
course I took. I've used Django in the past to build &lt;a href="https://github.com/AWegnerGitHub/IRVING"&gt;IRVING&lt;/a&gt; - a dashboard that allows users to run queries against many
database types and display the results in one location. The majority of this was done almost 6 years ago though. It was built
to assist in a job I no longer hold. Since then, I've ignored it and haven't used Django for a major project. I have used it to
test a small snippet of code here or there, but never a complete application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember liking Django. To that end, I decided to take Jose Portilla's &lt;a href="https://www.udemy.com/python-and-django-full-stack-web-developer-bootcamp/learn/v4/overview"&gt;Python and Django Full Stack Web Developer Bootcamp&lt;/a&gt;
course on Udemy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="thoughts-on-the-course"&gt;Thoughts on the course&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#thoughts-on-the-course" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am conflicted on how to rate this course. On the one hand, it covers a lot in the 30ish hours that the lectures take. Starting at
the very basics and moving through more advanced Django topics, it covers HTML and CSS then moves to Bootstrap, Javascript, the DOM,
jQuery, and Python before finally getting to Django. On the other hand, it moves through those basic lectures very slowly. Django isn't
even reached until two thirds of the way through the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lectures were a combination of hands on coding and an explanation of what the code is doing. The instructor types slightly
faster than me. This was a problem only at transitions between files, for example moving between an HTML file and a CSS file. I found myself
rewinding the video lectures many times around these transitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that I liked very early on in the lecture was the introduction of GitHub's &lt;a href="https://atom.io/"&gt;ATOM text editor&lt;/a&gt;. I've used this once before, for a job
interview that went very poorly (another story, for another time). I'd heard good things about it though. I used it throughout the course as a way to
force myself to use something other than PyCharm. Now that the course is complete, I have decided that I like ATOM, but not enough to switch from
PyCharm. It does have some nice features, especially with plugins, that I may utilize when building boiler plate code and templates though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="foundation-vs-django-content"&gt;Foundation vs Django content&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#foundation-vs-django-content" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The foundational material - HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, jQuery and even the Python - dragged on a little long for my taste. As I
mentioned above, this foundation took up the first two thirds of the course. I'd have preferred it if more time could be spent covering
other aspects of Django, especially some of the concepts that are thrown at the student in the last clone project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Django content, itself, was great. It started at basics like setting up a project and single application within the project and
moved through URL routing, templates, views and briefly touched on the admin side. There were advanced topics on class based views and
the debug toolbar, both of which are important when developing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't help feeling that important things were missed though. For example, the admin side is barely touched. It is incredibly capable, yet the
most that is done in this course with the admin backend is registering a model to appear. Groups and permissions aren't touched at all. Customizing
views in the backend aren't mentioned, either. Another thing that I was hoping would be covered as part of the "and much,much more!" bullet in the
course description was both &lt;a href="https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/1.11/topics/signals/"&gt;signals&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.djangoproject.com/weblog/2016/sep/09/channels-adopted-official-django-project/"&gt;channels&lt;/a&gt;, but they are not mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clone projects are useful in giving students a "real world" example that they are familiar with to bring everything they've learned together. There
are two such projects in this course, a blog and a message board/social media site. The blog one was a logical extension of the 5 parts that were
covered by Django. The message board, however, wasn't as useful. In an effort to be more "real world", the instructor missed a lot of steps in the
preceding foundational lectures. This project introduces multiple applications in the same project, but never introduced that concept previously
and doesn't expand on it much here. Instead, the project becomes a combination of speed coding to keep up with what's happening in the lecture and
copy and pasting code from the notes when the instructor does the same thing. I appreciate the more realistic project, but for all the time that was
spent building the foundation of Django knowledge, there is a big gap between the last lecture and this clone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="final-thoughts"&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#final-thoughts" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course was worthwhile, once I made it through the foundational courses. It was a great refresher for what I'd done 6 years ago. Either I did
things very inefficiently then, or Django has had a &lt;em&gt;ton&lt;/em&gt; of improvements (or both), but looking back at IRVING, I see many things that could be
improved. I'm not sure if I actually will though, just due to not using the application any longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The long foundational courses either should have been condensed. I would have rather had more focus on Django and covered more topics there. This
is especially true after completing the second clone project. New concepts were used in this project, but glossed over as "there is excellent
documentation on this", instead of the in depth explanations that were provided earlier in the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd recommend this course for the Django topics. However, if you are coming into the course with any type of web development background (even the
relatively basic one I have), be prepared to be bored during the first half of the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ude.my/UC-1VGWNREH"&gt;&lt;img alt="Python and Django Full Stack Web Developer Bootcamp Award" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/udemy-django-full-stack-bootcamp.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="review"></category><category term="technical"></category><category term="learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Review of Udemy's Deep Learning Prerequisites - Linear and Logistic Regression courses</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/deep-learning-prereq-linear-logistic-regression.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-03T10:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-05-03T10:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Andy Wegner</name></author><id>tag:andrewwegner.com,2017-05-03:/deep-learning-prereq-linear-logistic-regression.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My review of the Deep Learning Prerequisites - Linear and Logistic Regression courses on Udemy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;h2 id="course"&gt;Course&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#course" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/deep-learning-prereq-numpy.html"&gt;last review&lt;/a&gt; covered &lt;a href="https://www.udemy.com/user/lazy-programmer/"&gt;Lazy Programmer's&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.udemy.com/deep-learning-prerequisites-the-numpy-stack-in-python/learn/v4/overview"&gt;Numpy prerequisites course&lt;/a&gt; on Udemy. In my goal to learn more about NLP,
I'm continuing through the courses this instructor has designed. To this end, that requires two additional prerequisites: &lt;a href="https://www.udemy.com/data-science-linear-regression-in-python/learn/v4/overview"&gt;Linear
Regression&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.udemy.com/data-science-logistic-regression-in-python/learn/v4/overview"&gt;Logistic Regression&lt;/a&gt;. This review covers those two separate courses.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="thoughts-on-the-lessons"&gt;Thoughts on the lessons&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#thoughts-on-the-lessons" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two courses are each short three hour courses giving a crash course in how to perform linear regression analysis and logistic
regression analysis. The courses cover both the theoretical math needed and the more practical Python code needed. The instructor
states, several times, that simply copying the code isn't good enough in the later courses. The mathematical background is needed to
succeed later. With that in mind, I spent most of these lectures relearning much of the math. The instructor provides several detailed
"Theory" lectures and I found those helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the theory is introduced, the next step is applying this in code. The instructor's code is short and to the point. It shows the
what was just taught and provides efficient &lt;code&gt;numpy&lt;/code&gt; code to convert the theory into something workable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again, I'm happy with the instructor and their teaching style. I think this will go well with the future courses I'm planning on taking
that are by the same person. I'm continuing to brush up on those math skills that haven't been used in a while, but at this point, I am happy
with how everything is heading for this series of courses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've posted my &lt;a href="https://github.com/AWegnerGitHub/Deep-Learning-Prerequisites"&gt;IPython Notebooks&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub for all three of the courses related to the prerequisites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="final-thoughts"&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#final-thoughts" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am still looking forward to taking the &lt;a href="https://lazyprogrammer.me/data-science-courses/"&gt;courses designed by the Lazy Programmer&lt;/a&gt;. The series of prerequisites were very helpful in helping
me to catch up on the skills I'll need, but didn't know (or remember much of) ahead of time. With the actual content coming up, I am hoping
the lecture style and hands on coding sections continue be the same quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Linear and Logistic Regression courses didn't require much in terms of software - Python, numpy, pandas and matplotlib - but I still need to
decide how I'm going to proceed with the courses. I'm not sure whether or not I want to set up a Linux machine or a virtual machine. Windows doesn't
seem to play well with all the libraries I'll be needing. It may make my life easier too. So far, everyone seems to be using a Mac or Linux machine to
teach these courses and offer only basic "It may work on Windows" advice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ude.my/UC-OMSE1FD6"&gt;&lt;img alt="Linear Regression Completion Award" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/udemy-deep-learning-prereq-linear-regression.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ude.my/UC-XASAGYVJ"&gt;&lt;img alt="Linear Regression Completion Award" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/udemy-deep-learning-prereq-logistic-regression.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="review"></category><category term="technical"></category><category term="learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Review of Udemy's 'Deep Learning Prerequisites: The Numpy Stack in Python' course</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/deep-learning-prereq-numpy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-20T22:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-04-20T22:30:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Andy Wegner</name></author><id>tag:andrewwegner.com,2017-04-20:/deep-learning-prereq-numpy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My review of "Deep Learning Prerequisites: The Numpy Stack in Python" on Udemy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;h2 id="course"&gt;Course&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#course" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found &lt;a href="https://www.udemy.com/user/lazy-programmer/"&gt;Lazy Programmer's&lt;/a&gt; Deep Learning courses on Udemy. A couple of those seem very interesting, specifically the ones
about Natural Language Processing. I'd love to be able to enhance either my &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/can-a-machine-be-taught-to-flag-comments-automatically.html"&gt;comment flagging&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/zephyr-the-bot-that-watches-for-low-quality-vote-requests.html"&gt;Zephyr&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/can-a-machine-be-taught-to-flag-spam-automatically.html"&gt;SmokeDetector&lt;/a&gt;
with language processing capabilities. I also have tried, multiple times, to come up with a way to detect duplicate questions on
Stack Overflow, but my limited knowledge of true NLP concepts has proved to be unhelpful in that task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have the goal of getting to the NLP courses and completing a few other data science and machine learning courses this year. I've
picked out a few that look interesting and useful in either personal or professional projects. That will be my main focus in the next
several months. When I need a break from these topics, I may find another soft skills course to look at. Or, I have a play through of
Witcher 3 waiting for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start this journey, I need to cover some prerequisites. Data Science and Machine learning utilize several important libraries and
I need to know them or brush up my skills when using them. I took the &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/data-analysis-with-pandas-review.html"&gt;Data Analysis with Pandas&lt;/a&gt; last winter and found that helpful.
Lazy Programmer offers one covering the numpy stack. That's what I just finished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="thoughts-on-the-lessons"&gt;Thoughts on the lessons&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#thoughts-on-the-lessons" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.udemy.com/deep-learning-prerequisites-the-numpy-stack-in-python/learn/v4/overview"&gt;Deep Learning Prerequisites: The Numpy Stack in Python&lt;/a&gt; is a brief two hour course that gives a crash course in how to use numpy, pandas,
matplotlib and scipy. It touches each of these &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; briefly. The goal of the course isn't to get you intimately familiar with the libraries.
The goal is to get you to know the libraries exist and a few of their most common tasks. In this regard, it was very useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course also served as a nice introduction to the instructor and their teaching style. It is all hands on though, which I like. I prefer
to do the coding (and add my own comments along the way) to watching someone present a huge chunk of code and walk through that line by
line. I've posted my &lt;a href="https://github.com/AWegnerGitHub/Deep-Learning-Prerequisites"&gt;IPython Notebooks&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One other thing this course does is introduce users to the assumptions the instructor makes about the students. Machine learning and data science,
in general, have a lot of math behind them. The instructor assumes that students have the theoretical background for this and teaches how to
implement this math in Numpy. Note to self: Brush up on those math skills. I haven't used some of this in a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="final-thoughts"&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#final-thoughts" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an introduction course to the bigger &lt;a href="https://lazyprogrammer.me/data-science-courses/"&gt;"Deep Learning" courses&lt;/a&gt; that Lazy Programmer offers. It does it's job well and has increased my
confidence in the instructor. My last couple courses haven't been great and I'm happy that this quick two hour course was available. I'm looking
forward to taking some more of these courses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I will need to consider as I go through this course: whether or not to either set up a Linux machine or a virtual machine. Windows doesn't
seem to play well with all the libraries I'll be needing. It may make my life easier too. So far, everyone seems to be using a Mac or Linux machine to
teach these courses and offer only basic "It may work on Windows" advice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ude.my/UC-9CGD0JX8"&gt;&lt;img alt="Completion Award" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/udemy-deep-learning-prereq-numpy.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="review"></category><category term="technical"></category><category term="learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Review of Udemy's 'Become a Product Manager | Learn the Skills &amp; Get the job' course</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/become-a-product-manager-review.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-20T07:40:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-04-20T07:40:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Andy Wegner</name></author><id>tag:andrewwegner.com,2017-04-20:/become-a-product-manager-review.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My review of "Become a Product Manager  | Learn the Skills &amp;amp; Get the job" on Udemy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;h2 id="course"&gt;Course&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#course" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently finished the &lt;a href="https://www.udemy.com/become-a-product-manager-learn-the-skills-get-a-job/learn/v4/overview"&gt;"Become a Product Manager  | Learn the Skills &amp;amp; Get the job"&lt;/a&gt; course on Udemy. I had picked
this up in December during one of Udemy's frequent $15 dollars. I was looking to take something non-technical that covers
more of the "soft skills" I utilize in my job. I do a lot of software "product manager" work, without the title, at my job
and was hoping to brush up on those skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="thoughts-on-the-lessons"&gt;Thoughts on the lessons&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#thoughts-on-the-lessons" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course is billed as a 13 hour course, with activities and interviews with product managers. The course is taught by
Cole Mercer (a Senior product manager at &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/"&gt;SoundCloud&lt;/a&gt;) and Evan Kimbrell (founder of &lt;a href="http://www.sprintkick.com/"&gt;Sprintkick&lt;/a&gt;). The course is
packed with useful content, resources and interviews. I learned a lot and reinforced a lot of what I already knew. That
information will be incredibly useful at work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That glowing review said, I had a hard time getting through the lessons. Despite the amount of useful information, I found
the lessons to be...boring, at best. At worst, the instructors attempted to throw jokes in that just didn't work for this format.
That type of distraction made it hard to stick with the lessons. Additionally, the quizzes that cropped up occasionally, were
treated as a joke by the course creators. There were joke answers, there were joke explanations for answers and their were
questions unrelated to the content but instead about the instructors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, there are several points in the lessons that ask students to go the message board and provide feedback, do a quick activity,
and interact with one another. I did a couple of these. I stopped doing them when I didn't receive any responses from either other
students or the instructors. A closer look at the message board shows this is very common. I have to scroll back through a couple
"load more" clicks on the message board to find &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; posts that even have a response. The interaction I was hoping for from the
instructors just doesn't exist with this course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="final-thoughts"&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#final-thoughts" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The content in this course is amazingly helpful. There are links to articles that I'll be able to use for years. The information
in the lectures is also helpful, if you can get through the bland presentation of the material. The frequent, distracting, jokes and
lack of interaction makes this course less stellar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I'd consider this a middle of the road course. The presentation is what drags down this information packed course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ude.my/UC-XK0L2MOQ"&gt;&lt;img alt="Completion Award" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/udemy-become-a-product-manager-completion.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="review"></category><category term="technical"></category><category term="learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Review of Udemy's 'From 0 to 1: Machine Learning, NLP and Python - Cut to the Chase' course</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/loony-corn-machine-learning-review.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-12-28T20:10:00-06:00</published><updated>2017-04-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Andy Wegner</name></author><id>tag:andrewwegner.com,2016-12-28:/loony-corn-machine-learning-review.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My review of "From 0 to 1: Machine Learning, NLP and Python - Cut to the Chase" on Udemy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;h2 id="course"&gt;Course&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#course" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to squeeze one more course in before 2016 ended. This time I chose
&lt;a href="https://www.udemy.com/from-0-1-machine-learning/learn/v4/overview"&gt;"From 0 to 1: Machine Learning, NLP and Python - Cut to the Chase"&lt;/a&gt; by the LoonyCorn team on Udemy. This course was
a 20 hour overview of machine learning techniques. I've been interested in taking some more formal training on various
machine learning algorithms and this course sounded like it would be useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="thoughts-on-the-lessons"&gt;Thoughts on the lessons&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#thoughts-on-the-lessons" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was very disappointed in this course. The lessons had large portions of time that overlapped one another, the
background music was distracting, the instructor's speaking volume isn't consistent, the "coding" portions weren't
done in a way that allowed me to follow along, code was presented with bugs and the instructor glossed over
these with a simple "we'll fix those later". The theories were presented fairly well but really should have been
condensed into a handful of lessons instead of spread out so broadly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took me a few lessons to realize it, but the course notes - effectively power point slides that are hand written
during the lecture - and the instructor's voice were recorded at different times. Multiple times through the lessons,
the &lt;em&gt;exact&lt;/em&gt; same portion is used repeatedly. Lecture notes are "rewritten" or explained again. This repetition is used
ineffectively, as the instructor's voice isn't consistent within a single lecture. The repeated parts are either much
louder or much softer than the surrounding lecture material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My biggest disappointment, though, was with the coding exercises. I was hoping for some hands on activities. Instead,
the instructor spoke while the code - with all comments - was coded "live". The code was done quickly and offered no time
for me to both code and listen to the explanation. Like the lecture notes, the code and the vocal explanation was
recorded at different times. This means when a bug is encountered in the code, it is simply glossed over in the
explanation as an area they will return to later to fix. This was incredibly frustrating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="final-thoughts"&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#final-thoughts" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course wasn't worth my time. The theory portions were &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; good enough that I stuck with it hoping to pick out
something useful, but it never seemed to materialize. I did complete the course and don't feel I've learned anything
that I can apply elsewhere. In the new year, I'll be looking for another machine learning course that, hopefully, is
much better than this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ude.my/UC-9WXL1L1V"&gt;&lt;img alt="Completion Award" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/udemy-machine-learning-nlp-python-completion.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="review"></category><category term="technical"></category><category term="learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Review of Udemy's 'Data Analysis with Pandas' course</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/data-analysis-with-pandas-review.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-12-09T22:54:00-06:00</published><updated>2016-12-09T22:54:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Andy Wegner</name></author><id>tag:andrewwegner.com,2016-12-09:/data-analysis-with-pandas-review.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My review of "Data Analysis with Pandas" on Udemy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;It's been a few years since I finished my formal education. I've been getting the itch to take a few more structured
training courses, but don't have the desire to commit to another full university degree. Fortunately, there are a lot
of places online that now offer training and college courses (both free and paid). I'll be picking out a few and going
through them as my free time permits. I'll be sharing my thoughts on the courses in a series of posts with a review of
the course and, if available, a link to show what I produced during the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="data-analysis-with-pandas"&gt;Data Analysis with Pandas&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#data-analysis-with-pandas" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently completed &lt;a href="https://www.udemy.com/data-analysis-with-pandas/learn/v4/overview"&gt;Data Analysis with Pandas&lt;/a&gt; by Boris Paskhaver on Udemy. I use pandas both at work and in
personal projects and constantly find new things the library can do. This course is billed as a 19 hour course spanning
173 lectures. The curriculum looked like it covered both basics and topics I was less familiar with. It also helped
that the instructor was offering a coupon code on reddit to take the course for free. I decided to take the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spoiler&lt;/em&gt;: Even if this wasn't free, this class was worth the price. It covered a large part of pandas and did so in a
way that didn't make me tune out the instructor, even after 19 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="thoughts-on-the-lessons"&gt;Thoughts on the lessons&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#thoughts-on-the-lessons" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course starts a bit slow with your basic "How to install" tutorials. The entire course is done in a series of
&lt;a href="https://github.com/AWegnerGitHub/Data-Analysis-with-Pandas"&gt;Jupyter Notebooks&lt;/a&gt; and, obviously, requires that you have Python (the instructor uses 3.5), pandas and a few
other modules installed before we get to the good stuff. The instructor uses OS X during all lectures, but that has
no effect on how things are communicated to the student. Everything is done in the Jupyter Notebooks or at a &lt;a href="https://www.continuum.io/downloads"&gt;conda&lt;/a&gt;
prompt. This works the same across all major operating systems. The only reason I felt this was slow was because I
already had all of the requirements installed due to using the library before. I understand the need for this lesson,
though, and can't hold it against the instructor for needing to include this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that I liked about the introduction was that the instructor provided a series of CSV files we'd use
throughout the rest of the lessons. These CSVs were varied in size and composition. I thought this was a great way to
keep everyone on the same page. I've seen a lot of tutorials on pandas around the internet and most of them depend on
generating random data. By providing everyone with a set of CSVs it is much easier to focus on specific aspects of the
data and how certain functions work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="series-and-dataframes"&gt;Series and DataFrames&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#series-and-dataframes" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course really begins in Section 2 which is on the pandas &lt;a href="http://pandas.pydata.org/pandas-docs/stable/generated/pandas.Series.html"&gt;Series&lt;/a&gt; object. It covers what a series is, various
methods of creating one, and then goes over the various methods and attributes you can use on a series object. The
module covers 21 lessons and lays the foundation for the entire pandas library. Section 3, 4, and 5 cover
&lt;a href="http://pandas.pydata.org/pandas-docs/stable/generated/pandas.DataFrame.html"&gt;DataFrames&lt;/a&gt;. These sections cover 41 lessons. DataFrames are the heart of the pandas library. This is the object
you'll use most of the time, which explains the number of lessons that focus on DataFrames.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These lessons cover everything from selecting a series (column) in a data frame, adding a new column, dropping null
values and sorting values. More advanced topics include various ways of filtering a dataframe to only the data you are
interested in, applying a function to all values and working with either index labels or index positions. These modules
are the heart of the entire course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="text-data-and-datetime-data"&gt;Text data and DateTime data&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#text-data-and-datetime-data" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sections 6 and 10 deal with text data and datetime data. One complaint I had about these two sections was that they
were separated so much. Both types of data need to be operated on the same way in pandas. Namely, you have to add
either &lt;code&gt;.str&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;.dt&lt;/code&gt; when calling a string or datetime function. I also think that datetimes are important enough
and used frequently enough that getting a lesson in on how to properly use them early would make more sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That complaint aside, both sections cover their content well. There isn't anything ground breaking here, especially
if you've done any sort of work with either strings or dates in Python. The functions introduced all work as you'd
expect based on that experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DateTime section also provides information on how to work with date offsets and time deltas. Adding and
subtracting days/weeks/months is always important and the lessons cover how to do so pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="advanced-features"&gt;Advanced Features&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#advanced-features" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sections 7, 8 and 9 cover aspects of pandas that many will use as well. These cover ways to join and group multiple data
sets into a single data frame and the benefits of each method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MultiIndexes are not something I've used a lot, but after these 14 lessons I have already thought of ways I can
improve my code at work to utilize these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="panels"&gt;Panels&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#panels" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Section 11 covers a topic that was brand new to me: Panels. I have never used them or heard of them. A series is a 1D
data set, a dataframe is a 2D data set and a panel is a 3D data set. It is a group of dataframes. The instructor explained
this concept very clearly and worked through multiple examples of how to build and use a panel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this lesson, the panel we utilized was created by calling Google Finance for multiple companies. However, the panel
that was returned was not formatted the way I expected and it bothered me for several of the lessons. At first, this
was mentioned by the instructor in passing, and then seemed to be ignored. However, toward the end of the section, the
course covered ways of reforming the panel to be in a different format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="inputoutput-and-visualization"&gt;Input/Output and Visualization&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#inputoutput-and-visualization" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sections 12 and 13 covered the portions of pandas that my users see at work. The end result of data manipulation. I
produce visuals or excel documents and they are happy. The lessons cover how to export to CSVs and Excel (you need
an &lt;code&gt;ExcelWriter&lt;/code&gt;). It also covers the four most common visualizations I produce at my job - line charts, bar charts,
pie charts and histograms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of the scope of this course, but something I'll look into, is what else &lt;code&gt;matplotlib&lt;/code&gt; can do. We did very
little to customize our plots and I know that the library can do so much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="options"&gt;Options&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#options" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final section covers a few of the miscellaneous options pandas has. There isn't anything exciting in this section
and these 4 lessons are short. Placing them at the end is a decent spot for them, as it reminds you to go look at the
documentation to see what other options are available (there are a ton).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="final-thoughts"&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#final-thoughts" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I used a coupon code to take this course for free, I feel it was worth the listed price. The course covers 19
hours and 172 lessons. The may seem overwhelming at first, but the lessons are short, with most falling in the 4-7
minute range. There are a couple that reach the 10+ minute point, but they still held my attention the entire lesson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The instructor has the lessons structured in a way that allows you to pause and return at the start of any lesson
without having to re-execute a long series of code. Most of the lessons are self contained, where a data set is either
re-imported at the start of each lesson or a new one is introduced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only Section that didn't seem to follow this pattern was the visualization module. That module kept using code
from previous lessons. The section is less than an hour, but if you take a break you may need to rerun some of your
code in this section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 4 "quizzes" in this course. If you've worked through the lessons with the instructor, the questions are
very easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've now spent 19 hours (re)learning pandas and I feel that I've still just scratched the surface. I've learned a lot
that I'll be taking back to my code, but throughout the course I still got the impression there is much more to pandas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="notebooks"&gt;Notebooks&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#notebooks" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The notebooks that I created during this course are all available on &lt;a href="https://github.com/AWegnerGitHub/Data-Analysis-with-Pandas"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ude.my/UC-FB6LLMB5"&gt;&lt;img alt="Completion Award" src="https://andrewwegner.com/images/udemy-data-analysis-pandas-completion.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="review"></category><category term="technical"></category><category term="learning"></category></entry></feed>