<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Ponderings of an Andy - Stack Exchange Strike</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/feeds/stack-exchange-strike.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://andrewwegner.com/</id><updated>2023-06-21T11:00:00-05:00</updated><subtitle>Can that be automated?</subtitle><entry><title>Stack Exchange Strike - Personal Frustrations</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/stackexchange-moderator-strike-personal-frustrations.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-06-21T11:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-06-21T11:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Andy Wegner</name></author><id>tag:andrewwegner.com,2023-06-21:/stackexchange-moderator-strike-personal-frustrations.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Stack Exchange moderators are striking. The strike continues and my frustration grows.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;h2 id="recap"&gt;Recap&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#recap" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/stackexchange-moderator-strike.html"&gt;The Moderation and curator strike started on June 5.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stack Exchange has downplayed the effect of this to the press, while at the same time straight lied to the press about &lt;a href="https://openletter.mousetail.nl/"&gt;causes of the strike&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stack Exchange &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/stackexchange-moderator-strike-week-one.html"&gt;removed access to the data dump back&lt;/a&gt; in March but never told anyone until they were called out on it in early June.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href="{filename}2023_06_12_stackexchange_strike_update2.md"&gt;moderation team has elected three representatives&lt;/a&gt; to engage with Stack Exchange to solve these problems and end the strike.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stack Exchange launches the &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/stackexchange-moderator-strike-does-stackexchange-care.html"&gt;GenAI powered formatting assistant&lt;/a&gt;. The community quickly shows that it's very bad at it's job and it is shut down temporarily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="whats-new"&gt;What's new?&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#whats-new" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday Stack Exchange announced the upcoming launch of a new &lt;a href="https://meta.stackexchange.com/q/390463/186281"&gt;Prompt Design site&lt;/a&gt;. To say the community disliked the idea
would be an understatement. The community has pointed out that this will be incredibly niche, with very short term answers because
models update constantly. There are also concerns that this will essentially become a "write my prompt" (instead of "write my code")
site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agree with all of those concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also hidden in this announcement is another announcement. Stack Exchange is changing their method of launching new sites. This is
something that should have it's own announcement. This is a big deal and the community has been asking for improvements to the 
Area 51 incubator site for a decade. Unfortunately, the new method is to completely do away with all of the work that Area 51
does - building a community, setting intitial questions, helping to set scope, ensuring there is an audience for the topic - and
instead launching with a "Community Stakeholders" group that will do the work in either a private Stack Overflow for Teams instance
or a read only chatroom. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of those options entirely exclude people that may want to participate but don't have access. It adds barriers that don't exist 
on Area 51. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="my-thoughts"&gt;My thoughts&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#my-thoughts" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The announcement sets a launch date of July 26 for this new site. This is the day before the CEO talks at 
WeAreDevelopers World Congress. A venure where the company has been promising a major AI announcement for months. This new site,
combined with the formatting assistant failure from last week, is starting to show clearly what the company wants to do here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned in my &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/stackexchange-moderator-strike-does-stackexchange-care.html"&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt; that I was becoming more pesimistic that this strike doesn't end with resignations.
That continues to hold true. I also mentioned that Stack Exchanges seems to be keeping an eye on the Reddit strike - 
first with the blackouts, then with the John Oliver protests and currently with the NSFW toggles to prevent ads. Last night, 
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/6/20/23767848/reddit-blackout-api-protest-moderators-suspended-nsfw"&gt;Reddit started removing moderators&lt;/a&gt; as a result. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the lack of updates and communication from Stack Exchange to the moderators and curators in the last week, I can't help but 
think that something similar is being discussed at Stack Exchange. Time will tell, but my feeling is that Stack Exchange is going
to plow ahead with GenAI content on their platform. They are going to burn 15 years of trust and quality content and they are going
to do with regardless of what the community wants. If they community protests, they will be shown the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, I'm still pretty pesimistic about all of this. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Stack Exchange Strike"></category><category term="Stack Exchange"></category><category term="moderation"></category></entry><entry><title>Stack Exchange Strike - Does Stack Exchange Care?</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/stackexchange-moderator-strike-does-stackexchange-care.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-06-19T14:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-06-19T14:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Andy Wegner</name></author><id>tag:andrewwegner.com,2023-06-19:/stackexchange-moderator-strike-does-stackexchange-care.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Stack Exchange moderators are striking. It's been two full weeks and the progress toward resolution has been minimal at best.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;h2 id="recap"&gt;Recap&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#recap" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/stackexchange-moderator-strike.html"&gt;The Moderation and curator strike started on June 5.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stack Exchange has downplayed the effect of this to the press, while at the same time straight lied to the press about &lt;a href="https://openletter.mousetail.nl/"&gt;causes of the strike&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stack Exchange &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/stackexchange-moderator-strike-week-one.html"&gt;removed access to the data dump back&lt;/a&gt; in March but never told anyone until they were called out on it in early June.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href="{filename}2023_06_12_stackexchange_strike_update2.md"&gt;moderation team has elected three representatives&lt;/a&gt; to engage with Stack Exchange to solve these problems and end the strike.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="where-are-we-now"&gt;Where are we now?&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#where-are-we-now" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, I ended with a note that the data dumps should be restored by June 16. Good news. That has been completed and the &lt;a href="https://meta.stackexchange.com/q/389922/186281"&gt;dump was uploaded&lt;/a&gt; by June 16. It's 
progress, but after two weeks we have only accomplished one out of four tasks on the list of conditions to end the strike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A retraction of the of the prohibition of moderating GPT content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The private policy on GPT content that was issued to moderators must be revealed publicly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The data dumps must be re-enabled and SEDE and API access guarenteed.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stack Exchange, Inc. must communicate, gather feedback, and act on that feedback before making major policy or software changes to the public platform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've heard rumors that the second bullet may occur, but nothing has been done publicly. Thus, nothing outside of feedback from representatives to go on here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="gpt-content"&gt;GPT Content&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#gpt-content" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, June 15, &lt;a href="https://meta.stackoverflow.com/q/425162/189134"&gt;Stack Exchange enabled their "formatting assistant".&lt;/a&gt; To say it went poorly, is an understatement. There are currently 52 answers to that
question showing how it doesn't work. It's a thin wrapper around a version of ChatGPT or GPT4. It's also very, very bad at being a "formatting assistant". Instead,
it's &lt;a href="https://meta.stackoverflow.com/a/425176/189134"&gt;rewriting content&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://meta.stackoverflow.com/a/425165/189134"&gt;butchering code being asked about&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://meta.stackoverflow.com/a/425169/189134"&gt;making stuff up&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://meta.stackoverflow.com/a/425190/189134"&gt;answering questions&lt;/a&gt; and everything other than making formatting 
better. One user, Mithical, found the &lt;a href="https://meta.stackoverflow.com/a/425208/189134"&gt;prompt the formatting assistant&lt;/a&gt; is using. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one small postive that came out of this is that Stack Exchange did &lt;a href="https://meta.stackoverflow.com/q/425081/189134"&gt;communicate with the community&lt;/a&gt; a few days before this was released. This isn't enough 
though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="communication"&gt;Communication&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#communication" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why isn't one post enough? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behind the scenes it's become clearer to me that several staff members of Stack Exchange don't wish to engage with the community. I briefly touched on one of these
people in my &lt;a href="{filename}2023_06_12_stackexchange_strike_update2.md"&gt;last update&lt;/a&gt;. The public press has been out of the loop sounding, the internal reactions on moderation channels has been 
complaints that moderators are to negative. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course moderators are negative right now. &lt;em&gt;There is a strike going on because they are unhappy&lt;/em&gt;. The feedback from representatives continues to be filled with
road blocks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="where-do-i-sit-today"&gt;Where do I sit today?&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#where-do-i-sit-today" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it's becoming more clear that Stack Exchange is not interested in removing GenerativeAI content from it's site. It's actively building and promoting a tool
that utilizes ChatGPT under the hood. I am very surprised that they pulled the plug on the formatting assistant after two days. Previous negative feedback has been 
ignored and I fully expected this one to be as well. The problem with pulling the plug on this, is that CEO has committed to exciting announcements about AI this 
summer. If the community just showed that one of those AI projects was a flop, they are going to go even harder at getting the next one to succeed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this drags on into it's third week, I've become more pesimistic that this strike doesn't end with resignations. Reddit had a two day strike during this 
time period, and they are already threatening to replace community moderators. The Stack Exchange CEO has expressed their fondness for Reddit on occassion,
so I suspect that the action being taken over there is being considered here. Of course, the difference here is that Stack Exchange wasn't effectively shut down
by the strike like Reddit was. Sites didn't go dark. Instead, curators and moderators stopped curating and moderating. Everything is still available,
the sites are still working, it's just less tidy than usual. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Stack Exchange Strike"></category><category term="Stack Exchange"></category><category term="moderation"></category></entry><entry><title>Stack Exchange Strike Update 2</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/stackexchange-moderator-strike-update.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-06-13T23:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-06-13T23:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Andy Wegner</name></author><id>tag:andrewwegner.com,2023-06-13:/stackexchange-moderator-strike-update.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Stack Exchange moderators are striking. My update and impression of the last day.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#summary" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday's update summarized the &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/stackexchange-moderator-strike-week-one.html"&gt;first week of the Stack Exchange Moderator strike&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/stackexchange-moderator-strike.html"&gt;strike began last Monday&lt;/a&gt;
with an &lt;a href="https://openletter.mousetail.nl/"&gt;open letter to Stack Exchange&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend the moderators, and community curators elected three representatives to talk with Stack Exchange. Those talks started this week.
They went into these discussions to reiterate the four conditions to end the strike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A retraction of the of the prohibition of moderating GPT content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The private policy on GPT content that was issued to moderators must be revealed publicly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The data dumps must be re-enabled and SEDE and API access guarenteed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stack Exchange, Inc. must communicate, gather feedback, and act on that feedback before making major policy or software changes to the public platform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, where are we now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-update"&gt;The update&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#the-update" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="representatives"&gt;Representatives&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#representatives" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussions with Stack Exchange started off less than stellar, in my opinion. Quoting from the Vice President of Community at Stack Exchange, as 
relayed to those of us not in the discussions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"So in summary:  Cesar is my delegate for issues here, while I reserve final decision making to myself I"ve vested him with broad discretionary authority and we're meeting on a frequent (daily or multiple times daily) basis to clear any differences between us."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My take away here is that the Vice President of Community - a person who's job should involve &lt;em&gt;dealing with the community&lt;/em&gt; doesn't think this is 
important enough to attend. While I've worked with Cesar in my role as a moderator, this is just making Cesar the car salesman that has to 
"talk with the manager about your offer". It's a way for the company to drag this out and a way to make a the real decisions without moderation
input. I fully expect to hear from the community representatives that Cesar liked a proposal but the VP did not but that the VP wasn't around to 
discuss why not. I'd love to be proven wrong on that though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="data-dumps"&gt;Data Dumps&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#data-dumps" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data dumps are the third bullet on our list of things that must be restored. Good news! Stack Exchange will have those restored by June 16, 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was &lt;a href="https://meta.stackexchange.com/a/390200/186281"&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://meta.stackexchange.com/a/390202/186281"&gt;twice&lt;/a&gt;) by the VP of Community - the one not attending the talks above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...]
Our intention was never to stop posting the data dump, only to begin to collect more information on how it was being used and by whom - especially in light of the rise of LLMs and questions around how genAI models are handling attribution. However, it’s clear that many individual users (academics, researchers, etc) have an immediate need to access updated versions of the dumps. So we are re-enabling the automatic data dumps (and uploading the one that’s about a week overdue). We believe that this can happen by end of the day Friday. We will continue to work toward the creation of certain guardrails (for large AI/LLM companies) for both the dumps and the API, but again - we have no intention of restricting/charging community members or other responsible users of the dumps or the API from accessing them.
[...]
In the meantime, the data dumps will be re-enabled by end of day Friday. We will communicate here when that has been completed or if there are any delays. We will also post here prior to making any future changes to the dumps or distribution of the dumps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose now we wait to see if there are any "delays" before Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This message was confirmed by one of the Co-Founders that has since left Stack Exchange and 
&lt;a href="https://stackoverflow.blog/2009/06/04/stack-overflow-creative-commons-data-dump/"&gt;originally committed to these data dumps back in June 2009&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have confirmation via email from Prashanth that this is, indeed, &lt;strong&gt;the new official policy&lt;/strong&gt;. I'm glad to see it. Creative Commons is part of our contract with the community, and it should never be broken -- however, CC does need to address the AI issue in an updated license, in my personal opinion. [...] - &lt;a href="https://meta.stackexchange.com/questions/390201/what-is-the-current-june-2023-status-of-the-data-dumps-and-the-company-s-commi?noredirect=1&amp;amp;lq=1#comment1302765_390202"&gt;Jeff Atwood&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am happy with this concession and confirmation of the concession from our representatives, Stack Exchange and a Co-founder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it's telling that once again it's Philippe making statements that are lies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He's done it with posts to the press that I mentioned yesterday (moderators are depending on GPT detectors!). He's done it with the internal 
emails to his own coworkers. He's doing it again here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our intention was never to stop posting the data dump...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href="https://meta.stackexchange.com/a/390040/186281"&gt;directly contridicts that statement provided by the Stack Exchange Chief Technology Officer&lt;/a&gt; last week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stack Overflow senior leadership is working on a strategy to protect Stack Overflow data from being misused by companies building LLMs. While working on this strategy, we decided to stop the dump until we could put guardrails in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For being a VP of Community, the ability to communicate with the community is greatly lacking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="ai-policy"&gt;AI Policy&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#ai-policy" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much more progress has been provided by the community representatives. From what I have seen, Stack Exchange is pushing to call an end of this
with the promise of a new policy. But it's not done yet. They'll work on it with the moderators and once that's done, that will replace the current 
policy that started the strike. The representative mentioned they were pushing for a deadline on how quickly moderators would be able to commit to this 
change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, this is a way to end the community's moderation strike and agree to essentially nothing. It's another promise that something will happen. 
It gets the community back to moderation (which Stack Exchange employees have been doing for the week), and if they break that promise the effort to 
re-organize action has to start all over again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, I'm not agreeing to go back to utilizing my free time to perform moderation duties without knowing what the new policy is. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="where-do-i-sit"&gt;Where do I sit?&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#where-do-i-sit" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much like yesterday, I continue to re-evaluate my relationship with Stack Exchange. I'm really happy that the data dump has been restored. The messaging
around it though continues to erode my trust in the company's actions. This was also one of the easier items for Stack Exchange to agree to, even 
though it looks like a co-founder may have had a hand in resolving this as well. I don't know if that's true and I appreciate the work the 
representatives have done to resolve our first point of contention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's also very telling that the messaging doesn't mention the restoration in the context of the strike at all. If the company was attempting to 
build goodwill in this environment, I'd think they would point to the conditions in the open letter and tie the enablement of the data dumps directly
to that. Instead, we got a statement that says they didn't intend to stop posting the data dump, directly contridicting a previous statement saying
senior leadership decided to stop the dump.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazing.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Stack Exchange Strike"></category><category term="Stack Exchange"></category><category term="moderation"></category></entry><entry><title>Stack Exchange Strike - Week One</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/stackexchange-moderator-strike-week-one.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-06-12T09:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-06-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Andy Wegner</name></author><id>tag:andrewwegner.com,2023-06-12:/stackexchange-moderator-strike-week-one.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Stack Exchange moderators are striking. This is my my summary of the first week.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#summary" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A week ago, many &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/stackexchange-moderator-strike.html"&gt;Stack Exchange diamond moderators began a moderation strike&lt;/a&gt;. They have been joined by 
power users and curators. At the time of this post, there are over 1200 users that have signed the &lt;a href="https://openletter.mousetail.nl/"&gt;open letter to Stack Exchange&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This strike has been covered in a few news articles, but I suspect this week's actions against Reddit and their new API pricing
changes will overshadow Stack Overflow for a little while. That's fine with me. Perhaps cooler heads will prevail when there is 
less public focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Stack Exchange strike has been covered:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/ai-stack-overflow-content-moderation-chat-gpt-1850505609"&gt;On Gizmodo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/4a33dj/stack-overflow-moderators-are-striking-to-stop-garbage-ai-content-from-flooding-the-site"&gt;On Vice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://devclass.com/2023/06/05/stack-overflow-volunteer-moderators-down-tools-over-secret-new-policy-that-obstructs-removal-of-ai-generated-content/"&gt;On DevClass&lt;/a&gt; (with an inverview from a fellow Charcoal power user and Stack Overflow moderator)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The important thing in this set of articles is the public statement that was released by Philippe Beaudette, Vice President of Community (taken from the Vice article above).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A small number of moderators (11%) across the Stack Overflow network have stopped engaging in several activities, including moderating content. The primary reason for this action is dissatisfaction with our position on detection tools regarding AI-generated content. Stack Overflow ran an analysis and the ChatGPT detection tools that moderators were previously using have an alarmingly high rate of false positives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stand by our decision to require that moderators stop using the tools previously used. We are confident that we will find a path forward. We regret that actions have progressed to this point, and the Community Management team is evaluating the current situation as we work hard to stabilize things in the short term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They doubled down on this explaination in two meta posts. The &lt;a href="https://meta.stackexchange.com/q/389834/186281"&gt;initial statement&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href="https://meta.stackexchange.com/q/389928/186281"&gt;post with "data"&lt;/a&gt;. I encourage readers 
to spend a while reading through that second link and the answers. The community is skeptical of the conclusions drawn and 
have counter arguments and data scattered in the answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, during the week it was discovered that Stack Exchange stopped their quarterly data dump of all content. This was 
&lt;a href="https://meta.stackexchange.com/a/390040/186281"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; after a former employee stated that the data dumps were turned off in March. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stack Overflow senior leadership is working on a strategy to protect Stack Overflow data from being misused by companies building LLMs. While working on this strategy, we decided to stop the dump until we could put guardrails in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are working on setting up the infrastructure to do this correctly in the age of LLMs --- where we continue to be open and share the data with our developer community but work to set up a formal framework for large AI companies that want to leverage the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking for ways to gate access to the Dump, APIs, and SEDE, that will allow individuals access to the data while preventing misuse by organizations looking to profit from the work of our community. We are working to design and implement appropriate safeguards and still sorting out the details and timelines. We will provide regular updates on our progress to this group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id="where-are-we-now"&gt;Where are we now?&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#where-are-we-now" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the summary out of the way, where do we sit now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of midnight today, the users that have stopped moderation activities have &lt;a href="https://meta.stackexchange.com/q/390106/186281"&gt;selected three representatives&lt;/a&gt; to be our voice
in conversations with Stack Exchange and listed the conditions for ending the strike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A retraction of the of the prohibition of moderating GPT content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The private policy on GPT content that was issued to moderators must be revealed publicly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The data dumps must be re-enabled and SEDE and API access guarenteed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stack Exchange, Inc. must communicate, gather feedback, and act on that feedback before making major policy or software changes to the public platform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to point out that there is nothing here about GPT detection tools. That's because this isn't the reasong for the strike. 
Despite what Stack Exchange has said in their messages to the press, &lt;a href="https://meta.stackexchange.com/a/389856/186281"&gt;this isn't about detection tools&lt;/a&gt;. (I also have 
&lt;a href="https://meta.stackexchange.com/a/389825/186281"&gt;an answer&lt;/a&gt; on that question about the policy's origination.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The discovery that the data dumps were turned off has angered many people - those both already involved and others that learned of 
it this week. The fact that these were turned off over two months ago and nothing was said to the community has made the situation
even worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="whats-stack-saying"&gt;What's Stack Saying?&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#whats-stack-saying" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This section was added after original publication&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortly after publishing my thoughts with this article, internal Stack Exchange emails were published. These show how 
&lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20230612155947/https://jlericson.com/2023/06/12/internal_messages.html"&gt;Stack Exchange is communicating this with their employees&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I highly encourage everyone to read &lt;em&gt;those&lt;/em&gt; too. There is a lot of reading scattered around to get the full scope
of how unhappy the users of Stack Exchange are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it's telling that the company managed to copy and paste from the &lt;a href="https://openletter.mousetail.nl/"&gt;strike letter&lt;/a&gt;, but at the same time managed 
to completely ignore that this isn't about GPT detectors. Even worse, the company is spreading that falsehood to it's employees,
and the press. On top of that, has two teams - Community Leadership and Marketing - working on communications, yet no progress
has been made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="where-do-i-sit"&gt;Where do I sit?&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#where-do-i-sit" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/stackexchange-moderator-strike.html"&gt;last week&lt;/a&gt; that I've been here for over 13 years. I've applied and interviewed at the company. I've 
made friends with the employees and gotten recommendations during those interviews. I've built tooling to help &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/can-a-machine-be-taught-to-flag-comments-automatically.html"&gt;moderate comments&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/can-a-machine-be-taught-to-flag-spam-automatically.html"&gt;eliminate spam&lt;/a&gt; on the network. I've been here a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2019, I reevaluated my role on the network during Stack Exchange's last screw up. In that one, they managed to libel a moderator,
by name, to the press. This event still reverberates through the network today and serves as a brick that this current situation is
built with. Stack Exchange destroyed 10 years worth of trust and community relationships in that event. They've tried to rebuild it
over these last three years and have been marginally successful. That's gone again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I'm reevaluating how I utilize my free time again. It's not constructive to say I'll hand in my diamonds and walk away if the
conditions above aren't hit. But, it's worth noting that I agree with all four of those conditions. This is my free time I'm donating
and if the organization I'm donating that time to has changed their philosphy, I will take that into consideration as I reevaluate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think we are long past the point of "how it used to be" at Stack Exchange. The question I am asking my self is whether or not I
agree with the new direction the platform is going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated after the email publication, above&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading the email and FAQ that Stack Exchange sent to their employees, I am struck by how out of touch members of the company are.
Not the people that don't interact with the community. The people that should know the pulse of the moderation teams, the 
community opinions, and users in general - like the Vice President of Community. While I'm not surprised that they are 
down playing the strike, I am surprised that they are flat out lying to their employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stack Exchange should be called out on that and their employees should know that it's happening. Stack Exchange, Stack Overflow, Inc.,
is lying to their employees. The email presented was written after the strike started and contains information about all of the 
FAQ items mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Stack Exchange Strike"></category><category term="Stack Exchange"></category><category term="moderation"></category></entry><entry><title>Joining the Stack Exchange Moderator Strike</title><link href="https://andrewwegner.com/stackexchange-moderator-strike.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-06-05T01:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-06-05T01:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Andy Wegner</name></author><id>tag:andrewwegner.com,2023-06-05:/stackexchange-moderator-strike.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Stack Exchange moderators are striking. This is my reasoning for why I'm joining.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">
&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#summary" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm signing an open letter to Stack Exchange because those of us that volunteer our time and energy have 
been put in an impossible situation. On Stack Overflow we &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/stackoverflow-bans-chatgpt.html"&gt;banned ChatGPT created content&lt;/a&gt; almost immediately
after it was released. Theorectically, that is not longer in effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn't due to a change in community perception. Instead, it's due to an &lt;a href="https://meta.stackexchange.com/a/389583/186281"&gt;abrupt policy change&lt;/a&gt; on Stack
Exchange's part that was posted on May 30. It's important to note that this public policy does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; match
the guidance that was provided privately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The relevant portion of this public policy is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to help mitigate the issue, we've asked moderators to apply a very strict standard of evidence to determining whether a post is AI-authored when deciding to suspend a user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The private policy notes that "very strict" is essentially "don't moderate unless they explicitly say it was created by an AI".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="background"&gt;Background&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#background" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Stack Exchange CEO &lt;a href="https://stackoverflow.blog/2023/05/31/ceo-update-paving-the-road-forward-with-ai-and-community-at-the-center/"&gt;posted a blog post&lt;/a&gt; at the end of May 2023. In this post, they stated:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approximately 10% of our company is working on features and applications leveraging GenAI that have the potential to increase engagement within our public community and add value to customers of our SaaS product, Stack Overflow for Teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This goes against the community desire to &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; have GenAI content on the site. The CEO has not provided any feedback to the community,
other than a note that there is a big summer project with GenAI. The community reaction hasn't been positive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combining this announcement with the newly announced policy the previous day, and an astonishing inability to articulate more details or reasoning,
has producted a lot of unhappy moderators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I feel that the company has destroyed 3 years of rebuilding trust. Back in 2019, they destroyed this trust and nearly had a moderator
strike then too. That involved providing information to a journalist that had very limited context and due to that, presented a single moderator in 
unflattering light. The feelings from that have taken years to rebuild and even today that incident is cited as a low point, and users can point
out that singular incident when trust of the company plummetted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The public announcement to not moderate GenAI content contained this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through no fault of moderators' own, we also suspect that there have been biases for or against residents of specific countries as a potential result of the heuristics being applied to these posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's just wrong. Absolutely wrong. It is 100% inaccurate and Stack Exchange has offered no data to back this up. User country of origin, region in the world, or any kind of physical location is not available to moderators. We are present a flag and given information to the content that has been flagged. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="why-am-i-participating"&gt;Why am I participating?&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#why-am-i-participating" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So...my participation? Why am I joining in? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stack Exchange, and Stack Overflow, thrive due to the human element. It's userbase has been around over a decade and answered millions of questions across over 180 sites. The week ChatGPT came out, the community saw the bad results it can provide. For the past 6 months, we've continued to see how bad that is. The moderation teams across the network to generate a policy and get it approved by the company. I've reproduced it in full below, but as of this post it is still on the site and contridicts the new policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to completely ignoring the community's input on how they do not want GenAI on the site, the company ignored their own &lt;a href="https://stackoverflow.com/legal/moderator-agreement"&gt;moderator agreement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the assumption that the above will change at some point, the relevant section is pasted here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;```
Stack Exchange, Inc. agrees that it will:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i. Respect your privacy per the terms of the Privacy Policy for the Public Network.
   ii.  Get your explicit written permission before commenting to any media (including media outlets controlled by Stack Exchange Inc.) or independent reporters about you or your moderator actions as per our Press Policy.
   iii.  Allow you to resign your position for any reason without penalty or repercussions. As a volunteer, Stack Exchange, Inc. respects your time and will release you from duty should you ask.
   iv. Operate “Stack Gives Back”, an annual program giving to selected charities in honor of our moderators.
   v. Post previews for review of all new official policies in the Moderators Teams instance with the policy tag, marked with links to their public version once published, and maintain a listing of all official network-wide policies with links to them in the Help Center.
   vi. Announce changes to the moderator agreement no less than sixty days before the deadline to accept the new agreement with a period of at least thirty days for discussion and review.
   vii. Provide support for your questions, requests and concerns on the Moderators Teams instance and/or the Teachers’ Lounge, direct email to CMs, and content on Meta escalated to staff by whatever formal documented process is in effect at the time.
   viii. Respect your right to speak openly to question and challenge policy without reprisal so long as such speech does not break the Code of Conduct.
```&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The relevant section is &lt;code&gt;vi&lt;/code&gt;. There was no discussion period on this. No engagement with the moderators, or the community. Instead it was "effective
immediately." The best we've gotten so far is an "oops, sorry."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's not now something in a &lt;code&gt;/legal&lt;/code&gt; link should operate. If I can't trust  them to uphold an agreement they have in writing, why should I trust
them to uphold anything else? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-does-the-community-want-out-of-this"&gt;What does the community want out of this?&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#what-does-the-community-want-out-of-this" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the open letter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until Stack Overflow, Inc. retracts this policy change to a degree that addresses the concerns of the moderators, and allows moderators to effectively enforce established policies against AI-generated answers, we are calling for a general moderation strike, as a last-resort effort to protect the Stack Exchange platform and users from a total loss in value. We would also like to remind Stack Overflow, Inc. that a network that entirely relies on volunteers for its moderation model cannot then consistently ignore, mistreat, and malign those same volunteers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id="my-feelings-on-this"&gt;My feelings on this&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#my-feelings-on-this" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been on Stack Overflow and Stack Exchange for over 13 years. I've been a moderator on the network since 2014 and on Stack Overflow since 2017.
I've &lt;a href="https://andrewwegner.com/tag/stack-exchange.html"&gt;written about Stack Overflow a bit over the years&lt;/a&gt;. I've participated in &lt;a href="https://meta.stackexchange.com/questions/291301/can-a-machine-be-taught-to-flag-spam-automatically"&gt;Charcoal&lt;/a&gt;, the spam fighting community since 2015ish. This project
has automatically flagged more than 86,000 posts across the network since 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've applied to several jobs at Stack Exchange. I've interviewed for a couple positions. I have spent &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of time with the network, the 
community, moderators, and employees making this a great place for internet users to find their answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have helped to build the community/company trust that I mentioned above. I watched it crumble. I thought about leaving in 2019, but instead
spent the next three years working to rebuild that trust. I'm at the point again, where I see the company not understanding their community. At all.
It's sad that this cycle has repeated itself and it's worse that the company is, again, tossing their most engaged users under the bus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This strike serves two purposes in my mind - the first is the officially stated one. Do not all GenAI content on the network. It will erode the value of the network quickly. We've also demonstrated that ChatGPT and it's peers are not great at answering complex questions. But, second, and unofficially, 
this strike will represent a change for Stack Exchange to show whether or not they care about what the community has to say. This is, I believe, the last
opportunity for them to retract this policy and reflect on why they are over ruling so many communities that reject GenAI in their community. It's their
last opportunity to show they support their moderators and the human aspect of moderation. Failure to do either means that Stack Exchange has given up
on community building. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a volunteer for this community. I would love to continue that role, but this is the best way for me to show that GenAI is not the right path for the company to take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="whats-next"&gt;What's Next&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#whats-next" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On June 5, 2023 at midnight, moderator local time, the network will start to see moderation activities cease (or slow down). I will be part of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="gpt-policy"&gt;GPT Policy&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#gpt-policy" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This policy was crafted with the input of moderators and Stack Exchange. An important thing to notice is that the moderators are empowered to issue suspensions. This is something the new policy prevents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;```
Why posting GPT and ChatGPT generated answers is not currently acceptable&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Help Center article provides insight and rationale on our policy regarding the usage of GPT and ChatGPT on Stack Overflow. While this is the position of Stack Overflow staff, it’s meant to support the prior work done by moderators (namely, the temporary policy issued to ban contributions by ChatGPT).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stack Overflow is a community built upon trust. The community trusts that users are submitting answers that reflect what they actually know to be accurate and that they and their peers have the knowledge and skill set to verify and validate those answers. The system relies on users to verify and validate contributions by other users with the tools we offer, including responsible use of upvotes and downvotes. Currently, contributions generated by GPT most often do not meet these standards and therefore are not contributing to a trustworthy environment. This trust is broken when users copy and paste information into answers without validating that the answer provided by GPT is correct, ensuring that the sources used in the answer are properly cited (a service GPT does not provide), and verifying that the answer provided by GPT clearly and concisely answers the question asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The objective nature of the content on Stack Overflow means that if any part of an answer is wrong, then the answer is objectively wrong. In order for Stack Overflow to maintain a strong standard as a reliable source for correct and verified information, such answers must be edited or replaced. However, because GPT is good enough to convince users of the site that the answer holds merit, signals the community typically use to determine the legitimacy of their peers’ contributions frequently fail to detect severe issues with GPT-generated answers. As a result, information that is objectively wrong makes its way onto the site. In its current state, GPT risks breaking readers’ trust that our site provides answers written by subject-matter experts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moderators are empowered (at their discretion) to issue immediate suspensions of up to 30 days to users who are copying and pasting GPT content onto the site, with or without prior notice or warning.
```&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-letter"&gt;The letter&lt;a class="headerlink" href="#the-letter" title="Permanent link"&gt;¶&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The letter below was originally posted as an &lt;a href="https://openletter.mousetail.nl/"&gt;open letter to Stack Exchange&lt;/a&gt;. I've reposted it here 
for a record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;```
June 5, 2023
Stack Overflow, Inc. has decreed a near-total prohibition on moderating AI-generated content in the wake of a flood of such content being posted to and subsequently removed from the Stack Exchange network, tacitly allowing the proliferation of incorrect information ("hallucinations") and unfettered plagiarism on the Stack Exchange network. This poses a major threat to the integrity and trustworthiness of the platform and its content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We, the undersigned, are volunteer moderators, contributors, and users of Stack Overflow and the Stack Exchange network. Effective immediately, we are enacting a general moderation strike on Stack Overflow and the Stack Exchange network, in protest of this and other recent and upcoming changes to policy and the platform that are being forced upon us by Stack Overflow, Inc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our efforts to effect change through proper channels have been ignored, and our concerns disregarded at every turn. Now, as a last resort, we are striking out of dedication to the platform that we have put over a decade of care and volunteer effort into. We deeply believe in the core mission of the Stack Exchange network: to provide a repository of high-quality information in the form of questions and answers, and the recent actions taken by Stack Overflow, Inc. are directly harmful to that goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, moderators are no longer allowed to remove AI-generated answers on the basis of being AI-generated, outside of exceedingly narrow circumstances. This results in effectively permitting nearly all AI-generated answers to be freely posted, regardless of established community consensus on such content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In turn, this allows incorrect information (colloquially referred to as "hallucinations") and plagiarism to proliferate unchecked on the platform. This destroys trust in the platform, as Stack Overflow, Inc. has previously noted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, the details of the policies issued directly to moderators differ substantially from the guidelines outlined publicly, with moderators barred from publicly sharing the details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These policies disregard the leeway historically granted to individual Stack Exchange communities to determine their policies, by making changes without the input of the community, overriding community consensus, and outright refusing to reconsider their position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until this matter is resolved satisfactorily, we will be pausing activities including, but not limited to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="codehilight code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Raising&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ow"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;handling&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;flags&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;Running&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;SmokeDetector&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;anti&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;spam&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;bot&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;Closing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ow"&gt;or&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;voting&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;close&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;posts&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;Deleting&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ow"&gt;or&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;voting&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;delete&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;posts&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;Reviewing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;tasks&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ow"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;various&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;review&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;queues&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;Running&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;various&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;other&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;bots&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;designed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;assist&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ow"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;moderation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;such&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;as&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;detecting&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;plagiarism&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;low&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;quality&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;answers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ow"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;rude&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;comments&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until Stack Overflow, Inc. retracts this policy change to a degree that addresses the concerns of the moderators, and allows moderators to effectively enforce established policies against AI-generated answers, we are calling for a general moderation strike, as a last-resort effort to protect the Stack Exchange platform and users from a total loss in value. We would also like to remind Stack Overflow, Inc. that a network that entirely relies on volunteers for its moderation model cannot then consistently ignore, mistreat, and malign those same volunteers.
```&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Stack Exchange Strike"></category><category term="Stack Exchange"></category><category term="moderation"></category><category term="chatgpt"></category></entry></feed>